<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>

<!--
The Project Gutenberg EBook of The Tale of Solomon Owl by Arthur Scott
Bailey


This eBook is for the use of anyone anywhere at no cost and with almost no
restrictions whatsoever. You may copy it, give it away or re-use it under
the terms of the Project Gutenberg License included with this eBook or
online at http://www.gutenberg.org/license




Title: The Tale of Solomon Owl

Author: Arthur Scott Bailey

Release Date: 2005-09 [EBook #16663]

Language: American English

Character set encoding: ISO-8859-1
-->

<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "http://www.gutenberg.org/tei/marcello/0.4/dtd/pgtei.dtd">

<TEI.2  lang="en-us">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>The Tale of Solomon Owl</title>
                <respStmt><resp>Illustrated by</resp> <name>John Tenniel</name></respStmt>
                <author><name reg="Bailey, Arthur Scott">Arthur Scott Bailey</name></author>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Project Gutenberg</publisher>
                <date>2005-09</date>
                <idno type="etext-no">16663</idno>
                <idno type='DPid'>projectID42dc791b3f533</idno>
                <availability>
                        <p>This eBook is for the use of anyone anywhere at no cost and
                        with almost no restrictions whatsoever. You may copy it, give it
                        away or re-use it under the terms of the Project Gutenberg
                        License online at www.gutenberg.org/license</p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>unknown</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <encodingDesc>
            <projectDesc>
                <p>Produced by Roger Frank
                and the Online Distributed Proofreading Team at
                &lt;http://www.pgdp.net/c&gt;.</p>
            </projectDesc>
        </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <langUsage>
                <language id="en-us">United States English</language>
            </langUsage>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
                <change>
                  <date value="2005-5">May 2005</date>
                  <respStmt>
                    <name>Roger Frank </name>
                    <name>Online Distributed Proofreading Team</name>
                  </respStmt>
                  <item>Project Gutenberg Edition</item>
                </change>
    <change>
      <date value="2006-6">June 2006</date>
      <respStmt>
        <name>Joshua Hutchinson</name>
      </respStmt>
      <item>Added PGHeader/PGFooter.</item>
    </change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

<pgExtensions>
 <pgStyleSheet>
 .w95	{ }
 @media pdf {
 .w95	{ width: 95% }
 }
 </pgStyleSheet>
</pgExtensions>

<text>

<front>
    <div>
      <divGen type="pgheader" />
    </div>

    <titlePage rend="page-break-before: right">
        <docTitle>
            <titlePart type="main" rend="font-size: x-large">The Tale of Solomon Owl</titlePart>
        </docTitle>
        
        <byline>
            <lb />By <docAuthor>Arthur Scott Bailey</docAuthor><lb /><lb />
            Author of "The Tale of Sandy Chipmunk," "The Tale of Tommy Fox," etc.
        </byline>
        
        <docEdition>
            <hi rend="font-style: italic">Illustrated by Harry L. Smith</hi><lb /><lb />
        </docEdition>
        
        <docImprint>
            New York<lb />
            Grosset &amp; Dunlap<lb />
            1917
        </docImprint>
    </titlePage>
    
    <div rend="page-break-before: always">
        <p rend="text-align: center"><anchor id="image-fp" />
        <figure rend="w95" url="images/image-fp.jpg">
        <head rend="text-align: center">Solomon Owl Sat Up And Listened.
        </head>
        <figDesc><hi rend="font-style: italic">Frontispiece</hi></figDesc>
        </figure></p><p></p>
    </div>
    <div rend="page-break-before: right">

<index index="pdf" />

<head rend="text-align: center">Contents</head>
      <divGen type="toc" />
    </div>
        
    <div rend="page-break-before: right">
        <index index="toc" />
        <index index="pdf" />
        <head>Illustrations</head>
        
        <list type="simple">
            <item>
                <ref target="image-fp">
                Solomon Owl Sat Up And Listened <hi rend="font-style: italic">Frontispiece</hi>
                </ref>
            </item>
            
            <item>
                <ref target="image-001">
                Solomon Found Mr. Frog's Shop Was Closed</ref>
            </item>
            
            <item>
                <ref target="image-002">
                Benjamin Bat Asked Solomon's Advice</ref>
            </item>
            
            <item>
                <ref target="image-003">
                <q>It's All Right!</q> Said Solomon</ref>
            </item>
        </list>
    </div>
</front>

<body>
<div rend="page-break-before: always">
<pb n="001" /><anchor id="Pg001" />
<head>The Tale of Solomon Owl</head>
<p></p>
</div>

<div rend="page-break-before: always">
<index index="toc" level1="I - Scaring Johnny Green" />
<index index="pdf" level1="I - Scaring Johnny Green" />
<head>I<lb />
Scaring Johnny Green</head>

<p>
When Johnnie Green was younger, it always
scared him to hear Solomon Owl's
deep-toned voice calling in the woods after
dark.
</p>

<pb n="002" /><anchor id="Pg002" />
<p>
<q><hi rend="font-style: italic">Whoo-whoo-whoo, whoo-whoo, to-whoo-ah</hi>!</q>
That weird cry was enough
to send Johnnie Green hurrying into the
farmhouse, though sometimes he paused
in the doorway to listen&mdash;especially if
Solomon Owl happened to be laughing.
His <q><hi rend="font-style: italic">haw-haw-hoo-hoo</hi>,</q> booming across
the meadow on a crisp fall evening, when
the big yellow moon hung over the fields
of corn-shocks and pumpkins, sounded almost
as if Solomon were laughing at the
little boy he had frightened. There was
certainly a mocking, jeering note in his
laughter.
</p>

<p>
Of course, as he grew older, Johnnie
Green no longer shivered on hearing Solomon's
rolling call. When Solomon
laughed, Johnnie Green would laugh, too.
But Solomon Owl never knew that, for
often he was half a mile from the farm
buildings.
</p>

<p>
A <q>hoot owl,</q> Johnnie Green termed
him. And anyone who heard Solomon
hooting of an evening, or just before sunrise,
would have agreed that it was a good
name for him. But he was really a <hi rend="font-style: italic">barred</hi>
owl, for he had bars of white across his
feathers.
</p>

<pb n="003" /><anchor id="Pg003" />

<p>
If you had happened to catch Solomon
Owl resting among the thick hemlocks
near the foot of Blue Mountain, where he
lived, you would have thought that he
looked strangely like a human being. He
had no <q>horns,</q> or ear-tufts, such as some
of the other owls wore; and his great pale
face, with its black eyes, made him seem
very wise and solemn.
</p>

<p>
In spite of the mild, questioning look
upon his face whenever anyone surprised
him in the daytime, Solomon Owl was the
noisiest of all the different families of owls
in Pleasant Valley. There were the barn
owls, the long-eared owls, the short-eared
owls, the saw-whet owls, the screech owls&mdash;but
there! there's no use of naming them
all. There wasn't one of them that could
equal Solomon Owl's laughing and hooting
and shrieking and wailing&mdash;at night.
</p>

<pb n="004" /><anchor id="Pg004" />
<p>
During the day, however, Solomon Owl
he was quiet about it. One reason for his
silence then was that he generally slept
when the sun was shining. And when
most people were sleeping, Solomon Owl
was as wide awake as he could be.
</p>

<p>
He was a night-prowler&mdash;if ever there
was one. And he could see a mouse on the
darkest night, even if it stirred ever so
slightly.
</p>

<p>
That was unfortunate for the mice. But
luckily for them, Solomon Owl couldn't
be in more than one place at a time. Otherwise,
there wouldn't have been a mouse
left in Pleasant Valley&mdash;if he could have
had <hi rend="font-style: italic">his</hi> way.
</p>

<p>
And though he didn't help the mice, he
helped Farmer Green by catching them.
If he did take a fat pullet once in a while,
it is certain that he more than paid for it.
</p>

<pb n="005" /><anchor id="Pg005" />
<p>
So, on the whole, Farmer Green did not
wood-lot. And for a long time Solomon
raised no objection to Farmer Green's living
near Swift River.
</p>

<p>
But later Solomon Owl claimed that it
would be a good thing for the forest folk
if they could get rid of the whole Green
family&mdash;and the hired man, too.
</p>
</div>

<pb n="006" /><anchor id="Pg006" />
<div rend="page-break-before: always">
<index index="toc" level1="II - A Newcomer" />
<index index="pdf" level1="II - A Newcomer" />
<head>II<lb />
A Newcomer</head>

<p>
Upon his arrival, as a stranger, in Pleasant
Valley, Solomon Owl looked about
carefully for a place to live. What he
wanted especially was a good, <hi rend="font-style: italic">dark</hi> hole,
for he thought that sunshine was very dismal.
</p>
<pb n="007" /><anchor id="Pg007" />
<p>
Though he was willing to bestir himself
enough to suit anybody, when it came to
<hi rend="font-style: italic">hunting</hi>, Solomon Owl did not like to
work. He was no busy nest-builder, like
Rusty Wren. In his search for a house he
looked several times at the home of old
Mr. Crow. If it had suited him better,
Solomon would not have hesitated to take
that it was altogether <hi rend="font-style: italic">too light</hi> to please
him.
</p>

<p>
That was lucky for old Mr. Crow. And
the black rascal knew it, too. He had noticed
that Solomon Owl was hanging about
the neighborhood. And several times he
caught Solomon examining his nest.
</p>

<p>
But Mr. Crow did not have to worry
long. For as it happened, Solomon Owl
at last found exactly what he wanted. In
an old, hollow hemlock, he came across a
cozy, dark cavity. As soon as he saw it
he knew that it was the very thing! So
he moved in at once. And except for the
time that he spent in the meadow&mdash;which
was considerably later&mdash;he lived there for
a good many years.
</p>

<pb n="008" /><anchor id="Pg008" />
<p>
Once Fatty Coon thought that he would
drive Solomon out of his snug house and
live in it himself. But he soon changed
Solomon Owl&mdash;so Fatty discovered&mdash;had
sharp, strong claws and a sharp,
strong beak as well, which curled over his
face in a cruel hook.
</p>

<p>
It was really a good thing for Solomon
Owl&mdash;the fight he had with Fatty Coon.
For afterward his neighbors seldom
troubled him&mdash;except when Jasper Jay
brought a crowd of his noisy friends to
tease Solomon, or Reddy Woodpecker annoyed
him by rapping on his door when he
was asleep.
</p>

<p>
But those rowdies always took good care
to skip out of Solomon's reach. And when
Jasper Jay met Solomon alone in the
woods at dawn or dusk he was most polite
to the solemn old chap. <hi rend="font-style: italic">Then</hi> it was
<q>How-dy-do, Mr. Owl!</q> and <q>I hope
you're well to-day!</q> And when Solomon
Jasper, that bold fellow always felt quite
uneasy; and he was glad when Solomon
Owl looked away.
</p>
<pb n="009" /><anchor id="Pg009" />

<p>
If Solomon Owl chanced to <hi rend="font-style: italic">hoot</hi> on those
occasions, Jasper Jay would jump almost
out of his bright blue coat. Then Solomon's
deep laughter would echo mockingly
through the woods.
</p>

<pb n="010" /><anchor id="Pg010" />
<p>
You see, though not nearly so wise as
he appeared, Solomon Owl knew well
enough how to frighten some people.
</p>
</div>

<div rend="page-break-before: always">
<index index="toc" level1="III - Solomon Likes Frogs" />
<index index="pdf" level1="III - Solomon Likes Frogs" />
<head>III<lb />
Solomon Likes Frogs</head>


<p>
It was a warm summer's evening&mdash;so
warm that Mr. Frog, the tailor, had taken
his sewing outside his tailor's shop and
seated himself cross-legged upon the bank
of the brook, where he sang and sewed
without ceasing&mdash;except to take a swim
now and then in the cool water, <q>to stretch
his legs,</q> as he claimed.
</p>

<p>
He was making a new suit of blue
clothes for Jasper Jay. And since Jasper
was a great dandy, and very particular
Mr. Frog was taking special pains with his 
sewing.
</p>
<pb n="011" /><anchor id="Pg011" />

<p>
Usually he did his work quickly. But
now after every five stitches that he put
into his work he stopped to take out ten.
And naturally he was not getting on very
fast. He had been working busily since
early morning; and Jasper Jay's suit was
further than ever from being finished.
</p>

<p>
Since he was a most cheerful person,
Mr. Frog did not mind that. Indeed, he
was more than pleased, because the oftener
he took a swim the fewer stitches he lost.
So he sang the merriest songs he knew.
</p>

<p>
The light was fast fading when a hollow
laugh startled Mr. Frog. It seemed to
come from the willow tree right over his
head. And he knew without looking up
that it was Solomon Owl's deep voice.
</p>

<pb n="012" /><anchor id="Pg012" />
<p>
Mr. Frog tried to leap into the brook.
But when he uncrossed his legs, in his
haste he tangled them up in his sewing.
And all he could do was to turn a somersault
backward among some bulrushes,
hoping that Solomon Owl had not seen
him.
</p>

<p>
It is no secret that Mr. Frog was terribly
afraid of Solomon Owl. Some of
Mr. Frog's friends had mysteriously disappeared.
And they had last been seen
in Solomon's company.
</p>

<p>
As it happened, Mr. Frog had hoped in
vain. For Solomon Owl only laughed
more loudly than before. And then he
said:
</p>

<p>
<q>What are you afraid of, Mr. Frog?</q>
</p>

<p>
The tailor knew at once that he was
caught. So he hopped nimbly to his feet
and answered that there was nothing to
be afraid of, so far as he could see.
</p>

<p>
It was a true statement, too; because
Mr. Frog had not yet discovered Solomon
Owl's exact whereabouts.
</p>

<pb n="013" /><anchor id="Pg013" />
<p>
But he learned them soon; for Solomon
immediately dropped down from the big
willow and alighted on the bank near Mr.
Frog&mdash;altogether <hi rend="font-style: italic">too near</hi> him, in fact,
for the tailor's comfort.
</p>

<p>
Solomon looked at Mr. Frog very solemnly.
And he thought that he shivered.
</p>

<p>
<q>What's the matter? Are you ill?</q>
Solomon Owl inquired. <q>You seem to be
shaking.</q>
</p>

<p>
<q>Just a touch of chills and fever, probably!</q>
replied Mr. Frog with an uneasy
smile. <q>You know it's very damp here.</q>
</p>

<p>
<q>You don't look in the best of health&mdash;that's
a fact!</q> Solomon Owl remarked.
<q>You appear to me to be somewhat green
in the face.</q> And he laughed once more&mdash;that
same hollow, mirthless laugh.
</p>

<p>
Mr. Frog couldn't help jumping, because
the sound alarmed him.
</p>

<p>
<q>Don't be disturbed!</q> said Solomon
Owl. <q>I like all the Frog family.</q>
</p>

<pb n="014" /><anchor id="Pg014" />
<p>
At that remark, Mr. Frog started violently
That was exactly the trouble!
Solomon Owl was <hi rend="font-style: italic">altogether too fond</hi> of
frogs, whether they were old or young, big
or little.
</p>

<p>
It was no wonder that Mr. Frog swallowed
rapidly sixteen times before he
could say another word.
</p>

<pb n="015" /><anchor id="Pg015" />

</div>

<div rend="page-break-before: always">
<index index="toc" level1="IV - An Odd Bargain" />
<index index="pdf" level1="IV - An Odd Bargain" />
<head>IV<lb />
 An Odd Bargain</head>

<p>
While Mr. Frog was swallowing nothing
rapidly, he was thinking rapidly, too.
There was something about Solomon
Owl's big, staring eyes that made Mr.
Frog feel uncomfortable. And if he had
thought he had any chance of escaping he
would have dived into the brook and swum
under the bank.
</p>

<p>
But Solomon Owl was too near him for
that. And Mr. Frog was afraid his caller
would pounce upon him any moment. So
he quickly thought of a plan to save himself.
<q>No doubt&qdash;</q> he began. But
Solomon Owl interrupted him.
</p>


<pb n="016" /><anchor id="Pg016" />

<p>
<q>There!</q> cried Solomon. <q>You <hi rend="font-style: italic">can</hi>
speak, after all. I supposed you'd swallowed
your tongue. And I was just waiting
to see what you'd do next. I thought
maybe you would swallow your <hi rend="font-style: italic">head</hi>.</q>
</p>

<p>
Mr. Frog managed to laugh at the joke,
though, to tell the truth, he felt more nervous
than ever. He saw what was in Solomon
Owl's mind, for Solomon was thinking
of swallowing Mr. Frog's head himself.
</p>

<p>
<q>No doubt&mdash;</q> Mr. Frog resumed&mdash;<q>no
doubt you've come to ask me to make you
a new suit of clothes.</q>
</p>

<p>
Now, Solomon Owl had had no such idea
at all. But when it was mentioned to him,
he rather liked it.
</p>

<p>
<q>Will you?</q> he inquired, with a highly
interested air.
</p>

<pb n="017" /><anchor id="Pg017" />
<p>
<q>Why, certainly!</q> the tailor replied.
And for the first time since he had turned
his backward somersault into the bulrushes,
he smiled widely. <q>I'll tell you
what I'll do!</q> he said. <q>First, I'll make
you a coat free. And second, if you like it
I will then make you a waistcoat and
trousers, at double rates.</q>
</p>

<p>
Solomon Owl liked the thought of getting
a coat for nothing. But for all that,
he looked at the tailor somewhat doubtfully.
</p>

<p>
<q>Will it take you long?</q> he asked.
</p>

<p>
<q>No, indeed!</q> Mr. Frog told him. <q>I'll
make your coat while you wait.</q>
</p>

<p>
<q>Oh, I wasn't going away,</q> Solomon assured
him with an odd look which made
Mr. Frog shiver again. <q>Be quick, please!
Because I have some important business
to attend to.</q>
</p>

<pb n="018" /><anchor id="Pg018" />
<p>
Mr. Frog couldn't help wondering if it
wasn't he himself that Solomon Owl was
going to attend to. In spite of his fears,
to work to cut up some cloth that hung
just outside his door.
</p>

<p>
<q>Stop!</q> Solomon Owl cried in a voice
that seemed to shake the very ground.
<q>You haven't measured me yet!</q>
</p>

<p>
<q>It's not necessary,</q> Mr. Frog explained
glibly. <q>I've become so skilful
that one look at an elegant figure like
yours is all that I need.</q>
</p>

<p>
Naturally, Mr. Frog's remark pleased
Solomon Owl. And he uttered ten rapid
hoots, which served to make Mr. Frog's
fingers fly all the faster. Soon he was sewing
Solomon's coat with long stitches; and
though his needle slipped now and then,
he did not pause to take out a single stitch.
For some reason, Mr. Frog was in a great
hurry.
</p>

<pb n="019" /><anchor id="Pg019" />
<p>
Solomon Owl did not appear to notice
that the tailor was not taking much pains
with his sewing. Perhaps Mr. Frog
worked so fast that Solomon could not see
what he was doing.
</p>

<p>
Anyhow, he was delighted when Mr.
Frog suddenly cried:
</p>

<p>
<q>It's finished!</q> And then he tossed the
coat to Solomon. <q>Try it on!</q> he said.
<q>I want to see how well it fits you.</q>
</p>

<p>
Solomon Owl held up the garment and
looked at it very carefully. And as he examined
it a puzzled look came over his
great pale face.
</p>

<p>
There was something about his new coat
that he did not understand.
</p>
<pb n="020" /><anchor id="Pg020" />
</div>

<div rend="page-break-before: always">
<index index="toc" level1="V - The Cold Weather Coat" />
<index index="pdf" level1="V - The Cold Weather Coat" />
<head>V<lb />
The Cold Weather Coat</head>


<p>
Yes! As he held up his new coat and
looked at it, Solomon Owl was puzzled.
He turned his head toward Mr. Frog and
stared at him for a moment. And then he
turned his head away from the tailor and
gazed upon the coat again.
</p>

<p>
Mr. Frog was most uncomfortable&mdash;especially
when Solomon looked at <hi rend="font-style: italic">him</hi>.
</p>

<p>
<q>Everything's all right, isn't it?</q> he inquired.
</p>

<p>
Solomon Owl slowly shook his head.
</p>

<p>
<q>This is a queer coat!</q> he said.
<q>What's this bag at the top of it?</q>
</p>

<pb n="021" /><anchor id="Pg021" />
<p>
<q>Oh!</q> exclaimed Mr. Frog. <q>That's
the hood! Knowing that you spend your
winters here in Pleasant Valley, I made a
hood to go over your head.... You'll
find it very comfortable in cold weather&mdash;and
it's the latest style, too. All the winter
coats this year will have hoods, with
holes to see through, you know.</q>
</p>

<p>
Solomon Owl looked relieved at Mr.
Frog's explanation. But there was still
something more that appeared to trouble
him.
</p>

<p>
<q>How shall I get into the coat?</q> he inquired.
<q>It doesn't open in front, as it
should.</q>
</p>

<p>
<q>Another cold-weather style!</q> Mr.
Frog assured him. <q>It's wind-proof!
And instead of buttoning the coat, you
pull it on over your head.</q>
</p>

<p>
Solomon Owl said he didn't like that
style very well.
</p>

<pb n="022" /><anchor id="Pg022" />
<p>
<q>Then I can easily change it,</q> the tailor
told him. <q>But just try it on!</q> he urged.
<q>It may please you, after all.</q>
</p>

<p>
So Solomon Owl pulled the coat over his
head. And it fell down about him, almost
reaching his feet. But the coat did not
seem to suit him at all, for he began to
splutter and choke.
</p>

<p>
<q>What's the matter now?</q> Mr. Frog
asked him.
</p>

<p>
<q>I can't see&mdash;that's what's the matter!</q>
Solomon Owl cried in a voice that sounded
hollower than ever, because it was muffled
by the hood, which covered his head.
</p>

<p>
<q>I declare&mdash;I haven't cut the holes for
your eyes!</q> the tailor exclaimed. <q>Just
wait a moment and I'll make everything
satisfactory.</q> He clinked his shears together
sharply as he spoke.
</p>

<p>
But Solomon Owl told him that he
wouldn't <hi rend="font-style: italic">think</hi> of letting anybody use
shears so near his eyes.
</p>

<p rend="text-align: center"><anchor id="image-001" />
<figure rend="w95" url="images/image-001.jpg">
<head rend="text-align: center">Solomon Found Mr. Frog's Shop Was Closed
</head>
<figDesc><hi rend="font-style: italic">Illustration 1</hi></figDesc>
</figure></p><p></p>

<pb n="023" /><anchor id="Pg023" />

<p>
<q>I'll take off the coat,</q> he said. <q>And
I know now that you're a very poor tailor,
or you wouldn't have made such a mistake.</q>
He began to tug at the coat. But
he soon found that taking it off was not so
easy as putting it on. Solomon's sharp
claws caught in the cloth; and his hooked
beak, too, fastened itself in the hood the
moment he tried to pull the coat over his
head. <q>Here!</q> he cried to Mr. Frog.
<q>Just lend me a hand! I can't see to help
myself.</q>
</p>

<p>
But Mr. Frog did not even answer him.
</p>

<p>
<q>Don't you hear me?</q> Solomon Owl
shouted, as he struggled with his new coat,
only to become tangled in it more than
ever.
</p>

<p>
Still, the tailor said never a word,
though something very like a giggle, followed
by a splash, caught Solomon's ear.
</p>

<p>
<q>He's left me!</q> Solomon Owl groaned.
</p>


<pb n="024" /><anchor id="Pg024" />

<p>
<q>Mr. Frog has left me to get out of this
coat alone. And goodness knows how I'm
ever a-going to do it.</q> He threshed about
so vigorously that he tripped himself and
fell upon the bank of the brook, rolling
over and over toward the water.
</p>

<p>
He had a very narrow escape. If he
hadn't happened to bring up against an
old stump he would certainly have tumbled
into the stream.
</p>

<p>
Though Solomon couldn't see, he knew
that he was in danger. So he lay on his
back on the ground and carefully tore his
new coat into strings and ribbons.
</p>

<p>
At last he was free. And he rose to his
feet feeling very sheepish, for he knew
that Mr. Frog had played a sly trick on
him.
</p>

<pb n="025" /><anchor id="Pg025" />
<p>
<q>Nevermind!</q> said Solomon Owl, as he
flew way. <q>I'll come back to-morrow
and ask Mr. Frog to make me a waistcoat
and trousers. And then&qdash;</q> He did not
finish what he was saying. But there is
no doubt that whatever it was, it could not
have been very pleasant for Mr. Frog.
</p>

<p>
Just as he had planned, Solomon Owl
returned to the brook the next day. And
he was both surprised and disappointed
at what he found.
</p>

<p>
The door of Mr. Frog's tailor's shop was
shut and locked. And on it there was a
sign, which said:
</p>

<p>
TO LET
</p>

<p>
<q>He's moved away!</q> cried Solomon
Owl. And he went off feeling that he had
been cheated out of a good dinner&mdash;to
say nothing of a new waistcoat&mdash;and new
trousers, too.
</p>

<pb n="026" /><anchor id="Pg026" />
<p>
He had not been gone long when the
door opened. And Mr. Frog leaped nimbly
outside. He took the sign off the door;
and sitting down cross-legged upon the
bank, he began to sew upon Jasper Jay's
new blue suit, while his face wore a wider
smile than ever.
</p>

<p>
He had suddenly decided not to let his
shop, after all.
</p>


<pb n="027" /><anchor id="Pg027" />
</div>

<div rend="page-break-before: always">
<index index="toc" level1="VI - Solomon Needs a Change" />
<index index="pdf" level1="VI - Solomon Needs a Change" />
<head>VI<lb />
Solomon Needs a Change</head>

<p>
For some time Solomon Owl had known
that a queer feeling was coming over him.
And he could not think what it meant. He
noticed, too, that his appetite was leaving
him. Nothing seemed to taste good any
more.
</p>

<p>
So at last, one fine fall evening he went
to see Aunt Polly Woodchuck, who was an
herb doctor; for he had begun to worry
about his health.
</p>

<pb n="028" /><anchor id="Pg028" />
<p>
<q>It's lucky you came to-day,</q> said Aunt
Polly. <q>Because to-night I'm going to begin
my winter's nap. And you couldn't
have seen me again till spring&mdash;unless you
happened to come here on ground-hog day,
next February.... What appears to be
your trouble?</q> she inquired.
</p>

<p>
<q>It's my appetite, partly,</q> Solomon
Owl said. <q>Nothing tastes as it did when
I was a youngster. And I keep longing
for something, though what it is I can't
just tell.</q>
</p>

<p>
Aunt Polly Woodchuck nodded her
head wisely.
</p>

<p>
<q>What have you been eating lately?</q>
she asked.
</p>

<p>
Solomon Owl replied that he hadn't
eaten anything but mice since the leaves
began to turn.
</p>

<p>
<q>H-m&mdash;the leaves are nearly all off the
trees now,</q> the old lady remarked. <q>How
many mice have you eaten in that time?</q>
</p>

<pb n="029" /><anchor id="Pg029" />
<p>
Solomon said that as nearly as he could
remember he had eaten twenty-seven&mdash;or
a hundred and twenty-seven. He couldn't
say which&mdash;but one of those numbers was
correct.
</p>

<p>
Aunt Polly Woodchuck threw up her
hands.
</p>

<p>
<q>Sakes alive!</q> she cried. <q>It's no wonder
you don't feel well! What you need
is a change of food. And it's lucky you
came to me now. If you'd gone on like
that much longer I'd hate to say what
might have happened to you. You'd have
had dyspepsia, or some other sort of misery
in your stomach.</q>
</p>

<p>
<q>What shall I do?</q> asked Solomon Owl.
<q>Insects are scarce at this season of the
year. Of course, there are frogs&mdash;but I
don't seem to care for them. And there
are fish&mdash;but they're not easy to get, for
they don't come out of the water and sit
on the bank, as the frogs do.</q>
</p>

<p>
<q>How about pullets?</q> Aunt Polly inquired.
</p>


<pb n="030" /><anchor id="Pg030" />

<p>
At that Solomon Owl let out a long row
of hoots, because he was pleased.
</p>

<p>
<q>The very thing!</q> he cried. <q>That's
what I've been wanting all this time. And
I never guessed it.... I'll pay you for
your advice the next time I see you,</q> he
told Aunt Polly. And Solomon Owl hurried
away before she could stop him.
Since he had no intention of visiting her
on ground-hog day, he knew it would be
spring before he saw Aunt Polly Woodchuck
again.
</p>

<p>
The old lady scolded a bit. And it did
not make her feel any pleasanter to hear
Solomon's mocking laughter, which grew
fainter and fainter as he left the pasture
behind him. Then she went inside her
house, for she was fast growing sleepy.
And she wanted to set things to rights before
she began her long winter's nap.
</p>

<pb n="031" /><anchor id="Pg031" />
<p>
Meanwhile, Solomon Owl roamed restlessly
through the woods. There was only
one place in the neighborhood where he
could get a pullet. That was at Farmer
Green's chicken house. And for some
reason he did not care to visit the farm
buildings until it grew darker.
</p>

<p>
So he amused himself by making the
woods echo with his strange cry, <q><hi rend="font-style: italic">Whoo-whoo-whoo,
whoo-whoo, to-whoo-ah!</hi></q>
And now and then he threw in a few
<q><hi rend="font-style: italic">wha-whas</hi>,</q> just for extra measure.
</p>

<p>
Many of the forest folk who heard him
remarked that Solomon Owl seemed to be
in extra fine spirits.
</p>

<p>
<q>Probably it's the hunter's moon that
pleases him!</q> Jimmy Rabbit remarked to
a friend of his. <q>I've always noticed
that old Solomon makes more noise on
moonlight nights than at any other time.</q>
</p>

<pb n="032" /><anchor id="Pg032" />
<p>
The hunter's moon, big and yellow and
round, was just rising over Blue Mountain. 
But for once it was not the moon
that made Solomon Owl so talkative. He
was in fine feather, so to speak, because
he was hoping to have a fat pullet for his
supper. And as for the moon, he would
have been just as pleased had there been
none at all that night. For Solomon Owl
never cared to be seen when he visited
Farmer Green's chicken house.
</p>


<pb n="033" /><anchor id="Pg033" />
</div>

<div rend="page-break-before: always">
<index index="toc" level1="VII - The Blazing Eyes" />
<index index="pdf" level1="VII - The Blazing Eyes" />
<head>VII<lb />
The Blazing Eyes</head>

<p>
It was some three hours after sunset when
Solomon Owl at last reached Farmer
Green's place. All was quiet in the
chicken house because the hens and roosters
and their families had long since gone
to roost. And except for a light that shone
through a window, the farmhouse showed
not a sign of life.
</p>

<p>
Everything was as Solomon Owl wished
it&mdash;or so he thought, at least, as he alighted
in a tree in the yard to look about him.
He wanted no one to interrupt him when
he should go nosing around the chicken
house, to find an opening.
</p>


<pb n="034" /><anchor id="Pg034" />

<p>
To his annoyance, he had not sat long
in the tree when the wood-shed door opened.
And Solomon stared in amazement at
the strange sight he saw.
</p>

<p>
A great head appeared, with eyes and
mouth&mdash;yes! and nose, too&mdash;all a glaring
flame color. Solomon had never seen
such a horrible face on man or bird or
beast. But he was sure it was a man, for
he heard a laugh that was not to be mistaken
for either a beast's or a bird's. And
the worst of it was, those blazing eyes were
turned squarely toward Farmer Green's
chicken house!
</p>

<p>
Solomon Owl was too wary to go for his
fat pullet just then. He decided that he
would wait quietly in the tree for a time,
hoping that the man would go away.
</p>

<pb n="035" /><anchor id="Pg035" />
<p>
While Solomon watched him the
stranger neither moved nor spoke. And,
of course, Solomon Owl was growing hungrier 
every minute. So at last he felt that
he simply <hi rend="font-style: italic">must</hi> say something.
</p>

<p>
<q>Who-who-who-are-you?</q> he called out
from his tree.
</p>

<p>
But the strange man did not answer.
He did not even turn his head.
</p>

<p>
<q>He must be some city person,</q> Solomon
Owl said to himself. <q>He thinks he's
too good to speak to a countryman like
me.</q>
</p>

<p>
Then Solomon sat up and listened. He
heard a scratching sound. And soon he
saw a plump figure crawl right up into his
tree-top.
</p>

<p>
It was Fatty Coon!
</p>

<p>
<q>What are you doing here?</q> Solomon
Owl asked in a low voice, which was not
any too pleasant.
</p>

<p>
<q>I'm out for an airing,</q> Fatty answered.
<q>Beautiful night&mdash;isn't it?</q>
</p>

<pb n="036" /><anchor id="Pg036" />
<p>
But Solomon Owl was not interested in
the weather. <q>I don't suppose you've
come down here to get a chicken, have
you?</q> he inquired.
</p>

<p>
Fatty Coon seemed greatly surprised at
the question.
</p>

<p>
<q>Why&mdash;no!</q> he exclaimed. <q>But now
that you speak of it, it reminds me
that Farmer Green's saving a pullet for
me. He was heard to say not long ago
that he would like to catch me taking one
of his hens. So he must have one for me.
And I don't want to disappoint him.</q>
</p>

<p>
At first Solomon Owl didn't know what
answer to make. But at last he turned
his head toward Fatty.
</p>

<p>
<q>Why don't you go and get your pullet
now?</q> he asked.
</p>

<pb n="037" /><anchor id="Pg037" />
<p>
<q>There's that man down below, with the
glaring eyes&mdash;</q> said Fatty Coon. <q>I've
been waiting around here for quite a long
time and he hasn't looked away from the
chicken house even once.... Do you
know him?</q>
</p>

<p>
<q>No! And I don't want to!</q> said Solomon
Owl.
</p>

<p>
<q>S-sh!</q> Fatty Coon held up a warning
hand. <q>Who's that?</q> he asked, peering
down at a dark object at the foot of their
tree.
</p>

<p>
Then both he and Solomon saw that it
was Tommy Fox, sitting on his haunches
and staring at the big head, with its blazing
eyes and nose and mouth.
</p>

<p>
<q>Not looking for chickens, I suppose?</q>
Solomon Owl called in a low tone, which
was hardly more than a whisper.
</p>

<p>
But Tommy Fox's sharp ears heard him
easily. And he looked up, licking his
chops as if he were very hungry indeed.
And all the while the stranger continued
to stare straight at the chicken house, as
if he did not intend to let anybody go
</p>

<pb n="038" /><anchor id="Pg038" />
<p>
prowling about that long, low building to
steal any of Farmer Green's poultry.
</p>

<p>
It was no wonder that the three chicken-lovers
(two in the tree and one beneath it)
hesitated. If the queer man had only
spoken they might not have been so timid.
But he said never a word.
</p>

<pb n="039" /><anchor id="Pg039" />
</div>


<div rend="page-break-before: always">
<index index="toc" level1="VIII - Watching The Chickens" />
<index index="pdf" level1="VIII - Watching The Chickens" />
<head>VIII<lb />
Watching The Chickens</head>


<p>
Solomon Owl and Fatty Coon couldn't
help laughing at what Tommy Fox said to
them, as they sat in their tree near the
farmhouse, looking down at him in the
moonlight.
</p>

<p>
<q>I'm here to watch Farmer Green's
chickens for him&mdash;</q> said he&mdash;<q>to see that
no rat&mdash;or anybody else&mdash;runs away with
a pullet.</q>
</p>

<pb n="040" /><anchor id="Pg040" />
<p>
<q>Farmer Green has someone else watching
for him to-night,</q> said Solomon Owl,
when he had stopped laughing. <q>There's
that strange man! You can see how he
keeps his glaring eyes fixed on the chicken
house. And unless I'm mistaken, he's on
the lookout for <hi rend="font-style: italic">you</hi>.</q>
</p>

<p>
<q>No such thing!</q> Tommy Fox snapped.
And he looked up at Solomon as if he
wished that he could climb the tree.
</p>

<p>
<q>Here comes somebody else!</q> Fatty
Coon exclaimed suddenly. His keen eyes
had caught sight of Jimmy Rabbit, hopping
along on his way to the vegetable garden,
to see if he couldn't find a stray cabbage
or a turnip.
</p>

<p>
Solomon Owl called to him. Whereupon,
Jimmy Rabbit promptly sat up and
looked at the odd trio. If it hadn't been
for Tommy Fox he would have drawn
nearer.
</p>

<p>
<q>Do you know that stranger?</q> Solomon
Owl asked him, pointing out the horrible
head to Jimmy.
</p>

<p>
<q>I haven't the pleasure,</q> said Jimmy
Rabbit, after he had taken a good look.
</p>


<pb n="041" /><anchor id="Pg041" />

<p>
<q>Well,</q> said Solomon, <q>won't you
kindly speak to him; and ask him to go
away?</q>
</p>

<p>
<q>Certainly!</q> answered Jimmy Rabbit,
who always tried to be obliging.
</p>

<p>
<q>I hope the stranger won't eat him,</q>
remarked Tommy Fox, <q>because I hope
to do that some day, myself.</q>
</p>

<p>
It was queer&mdash;but Jimmy Rabbit was
the only one of the four that wasn't afraid
of those glaring features. He hopped
straight up to the big round head, which
was just a bit higher than one of the fence
posts, against which the stranger seemed
to be leaning. And after a moment or two
Jimmy Rabbit called to Solomon and
Fatty and Tommy Fox:
</p>

<p>
<q>He won't go away! He's going to stay
right where he is!</q>
</p>

<p>
<q>Come here a minute!</q> said Tommy.
</p>

<p>
Jimmy Rabbit shook his head.
</p>


<pb n="042" /><anchor id="Pg042" />

<p>
<q>You come over here!</q> he answered.
And he did not stir from the side of the
stranger. He knew very well that Tommy
Fox was afraid of the man with the head
with the glaring eyes.
</p>

<p>
As for Tommy Fox, he did not even
reply&mdash;that is, to Jimmy Rabbit. But he
spoke his mind freely enough to his two
friends in the tree.
</p>

<p>
<q>It seems to me one of you ought to do
something,</q> said he. <q>We'll eat no pullets
to-night if we can't get rid of this meddlesome
stranger.</q>
</p>

<p>
Fatty Coon quite agreed with him.
</p>

<p>
<q>The one who was here first is the one
to act!</q> Fatty declared. <q>That's <hi rend="font-style: italic">you</hi>!</q>
he told Solomon Owl.
</p>

<p>
So Solomon Owl felt most uncomfortable.
</p>

<pb n="043" /><anchor id="Pg043" />
<p>
<q>I don't know what I can do,</q> he said.
<q>I spoke to the stranger&mdash;asked him who
he was. And he wouldn't answer me.</q>
</p>

<p>
<q>Can't you frighten him away?</q> Tommy
Fox inquired. <q>Fly right over his
head and give him a blow with your wing
as you pass!</q>
</p>

<p>
Solomon Owl coughed. He was embarrassed,
to say the least.
</p>

<p>
<q>He's afraid!</q> Fatty Coon cried. And
both he and Tommy Fox kept repeating,
over and over again, <q>He's afraid! He's
afraid! He's afraid!</q>
</p>

<p>
It was really more than Solomon Owl
could stand.
</p>

<pb n="044" /><anchor id="Pg044" />
<p>
<q>I'm not!</q> he retorted angrily.
<q>Watch me and you'll see!</q> And without
another word he darted out of the tree
and swooped down upon the stranger, just
brushing the top of his head. Solomon
Owl knew at once that he had knocked
something off the top of that dreadful
head&mdash;something that fell to the ground
and made Jimmy Rabbit jump nervously.
</p>

<p>
Then Solomon returned to his perch in
the tree.
</p>

<p>
<q>He hasn't moved,</q> he said. <q>But I
knocked off his hat.</q>
</p>

<p>
<q>You took off the top of his head!</q>
cried Fatty Coon in great excitement.
<q>Look! The inside of his head is afire.</q>
</p>

<p>
And peering down from the tree-top,
Solomon Owl saw that Fatty Coon had
told the truth.
</p>


<pb n="045" /><anchor id="Pg045" />
</div>

<div rend="page-break-before: always">
<index index="toc" level1="IX - Hallowe'en" />
<index index="pdf" level1="IX - Hallowe'en" />
<head>IX<lb />
Hallowe'en</head>

<p>
Solomon Owl was afraid of fire. And
when he looked down from his perch in the
tree and saw, through the hole in the stranger's
crown, that all was aglow inside his
big, round head, Solomon couldn't help
voicing his horror. He <q><hi rend="font-style: italic">whoo-whooed</hi></q>
so loudly that Tommy Fox, at the foot of
the tree, asked him what on earth was the
matter.
</p>

<pb n="046" /><anchor id="Pg046" />
<p>
<q>His head's all afire!</q> Solomon Owl
told him. <q>That's what makes his eyes
glare so. And that's why the fire shines
through his mouth and his nose, too. It's
no wonder he didn't answer my question&mdash;for, 
of course, his tongue must certainly
be burned to a cinder.</q>
</p>

<p>
<q>Then it ought to be safe for anybody
to enter the chicken house,</q> Tommy Fox
observed. <q>What could the stranger do,
when he's in such a fix?</q>
</p>

<p>
<q>He could set the chicken house afire, if
he followed you inside,</q> replied Solomon
Owl wisely. <q>And I, for one, am not going
near the pullets to-night.</q>
</p>

<p>
<q>Nor I!</q> Fatty Coon echoed. <q>I'm going
straight to the cornfield. The corn is
still standing there in shocks; and I ought
to find enough ears to make a good meal.</q>
</p>

<p>
But Solomon Owl and Tommy Fox were
not interested in corn. They never ate it.
And so it is not surprising that they should
be greatly disappointed. After a person
has his mouth all made up for chicken it
is hard to think of anything that would
taste even half as good.
</p>


<pb n="047" /><anchor id="Pg047" />

<p>
<q>It's queer he doesn't go and hold his
head under the pump,</q> said Solomon Owl.
<q>That's what I should do, if I were he.</q>
</p>

<p>
<q>Jimmy Rabbit had better not go too
near him, or he'll get singed,</q> said Tommy
Fox, anxiously. <q>I don't want anything
to happen to <hi rend="font-style: italic">him</hi>.</q>
</p>

<p>
<q>Jimmy Rabbit is very careless,</q> Solomon
declared. <q>I don't see what he's
thinking of&mdash;going so near a fire! It
makes me altogether too nervous to stay
here. And I'm going away at once.</q>
</p>

<p>
Tommy Fox said that he felt the same
way. And the moment Fatty Coon, with
his sharp claws, started to crawl down the
tree on his way to the cornfield, Tommy
Fox hurried off without even stopping to
say good-bye.
</p>

<p>
<q><hi rend="font-style: italic">Haw-haw-haw-hoo</hi>!</q> laughed Solomon
Owl. <q>Tommy Fox is afraid of
you!</q> he told Fatty Coon.
</p>


<pb n="048" /><anchor id="Pg048" />

<p>
But Fatty didn't seem to hear him. He
was thinking only of the supper of corn
that he was going to have.
</p>

<p>
<q>Better come away!</q> Solomon Owl called
to Jimmy Rabbit, turning his head toward
the fence where Jimmy had been
lingering near the hot-headed stranger.
</p>

<p>
But Jimmy Rabbit didn't answer him,
either. He was no longer there. The moment
he had seen Tommy Fox bounding
off across the meadow Jimmy had started
at once for Farmer Green's vegetable garden.
</p>

<p>
So Solomon Owl was the last to leave.
</p>

<p>
<q>There's really nothing else I can do,</q>
he remarked to himself. <q>I don't know
what Aunt Polly Woodchuck would say if
she knew that I didn't follow her advice
to-night and eat a pullet for my supper.... But
I've tried my best.... And
that's all anybody can do.</q>
</p>


<pb n="049" /><anchor id="Pg049" />

<p>
Solomon Owl was upset all the rest of
that night. And just before daybreak he
visited the farmyard again, to see whether
the strange man with the flaring head still
watched the chicken house. And Solomon
found that he had vanished.
</p>

<p>
So Solomon Owl alighted on the fence.
There was nothing there except a hollowed-out
pumpkin, with a few holes cut
in it, which someone had left on one of the
fence-posts.
</p>

<p>
<q>Good!</q> said he. <q>Maybe I can get my
pullet after all!</q> He turned to fly to the
chicken house. But just then the woodshed
door opened again. And Farmer
Green stepped outside, with a lantern in
his hand. He was going to the barn to
milk the cows. But Solomon Owl did not
wait to learn anything more.
</p>

<pb n="050" /><anchor id="Pg050" />
<p>
He hurried away to his house among
the hemlocks. And having quickly settled
himself for a good nap, he was soon fast
asleep.
</p>

<p>
That was how Johnnie Green's jack-o'-lantern
kept Tommy Fox and Fatty Coon
and Solomon Owl from taking any chickens
on Hallowe'en.
</p>


<pb n="051" /><anchor id="Pg051" />
</div>

<div rend="page-break-before: always">
<index index="toc" level1="X - A Troublesome Wishbone" />
<index index="pdf" level1="X - A Troublesome Wishbone" />
<head>X<lb />
A Troublesome Wishbone</head>

<p>
Solomon Owl had pains&mdash;sharp pains&mdash;underneath
his waistcoat. And not knowing
what else to do, he set off at once for
Aunt Polly Woodchuck's house under the
hill, in the pasture, which he had not visited
since the previous fall. Luckily, he
found the old lady at home. And quickly
he told her of his trouble.
</p>

<p>
<q>What have you been eating?</q> she inquired.
</p>

<p>
<q>I've followed your advice. I've been
eating chickens,</q> said he&mdash;<q>very small
chickens, because they were all I could
get.</q>
</p>


<pb n="052" /><anchor id="Pg052" />

<p>
Aunt Polly Woodchuck, who was an
herb doctor&mdash;and a good one&mdash;regarded
him through her spectacles.
</p>

<p>
<q>I'm afraid,</q> said she, <q>you don't chew
your food properly. Bolting one's food is
very harmful. It's as bad as not eating
anything at all, almost.</q>
</p>

<p>
Solomon Owl showed plainly that her
remark surprised him.
</p>

<p>
<q>Why,</q> he exclaimed, <q>I always swallow
my food whole&mdash;when it isn't too big!</q>
</p>

<p>
<q>Gracious me!</q> cried Aunt Polly,
throwing up both her hands. <q>It's no
wonder you're ill. It's no wonder you
have pains; and now I know exactly
what's the matter with you. You have a
wishbone inside you. I can feel it!</q> she
told him, as she prodded him in the waistcoat.
</p>

<p>
<q>I wish you could get it out for me!</q>
said Solomon with a look of distress.
</p>


<pb n="053" /><anchor id="Pg053" />

<p>
<q>All the wishing in the world won't
help you,</q> she answered, <q>unless we can
find some way of removing the wishbone
so you can wish on that. Then I'm sure
you would feel better at once.</q>
</p>

<p>
<q>This is strange,</q> Solomon mused.
<q>All my life I've been swallowing my food
without chewing it. And it has never
given me any trouble before.... What
shall I do?</q>
</p>

<p>
<q>Don't eat anything for a week,</q> she
directed. <q>And fly against tree-trunks as
hard as you can. Then come back here
after seven days.</q>
</p>

<p>
Solomon Owl went off in a most doleful
frame of mind. It seemed to him that he
had never seen so many mice and frogs
and chipmunks as he came across during
the following week. But he didn't dare
catch a single one, on account of what
Aunt Polly Woodchuck had said.
</p>


<pb n="054" /><anchor id="Pg054" />

<p>
His pains, however, grew less from day
to day&mdash;at least, the pains that had first
troubled him. But he had others to take
their place. Hunger pangs, these were!
And they were almost as bad as those that
had sent him hurrying to see Aunt Polly
Woodchuck.
</p>

<p>
On the whole, Solomon passed a very
unhappy week. Flying head foremost
into tree-trunks (as Aunt Polly had instructed
him to do) gave him many bumps
and bruises. So he was glad when the time
came for him to return to her house in the
pasture.
</p>

<pb n="055" /><anchor id="Pg055" />
<p>
Solomon's neighbors had been so interested
in watching him that they were all
sorry when he ceased his strange actions.
Indeed, there was a rumor that Solomon
had become very angry with Farmer
Green and that he was trying to knock
down some of Farmer Green's trees. Before 
the end of that unpleasant week Solomon
had often noticed as many as twenty-four
of the forest folk following him
about, hoping to see a tree fall.
</p>

<p>
But they were all disappointed. However,
they enjoyed the sight of Solomon
hurling himself against tree-trunks. And
the louder he groaned, the more people
gathered around him.
</p>


<pb n="056" /><anchor id="Pg056" />
</div>

<div rend="page-break-before: always">
<index index="toc" level1="XI - Cured At Last" />
<index index="pdf" level1="XI - Cured At Last" />
<head>XI<lb />
Cured At Last</head>

<p>
<q>How do you feel now?</q> Aunt Polly
Woodchuck asked Solomon Owl, when he
had come back to her house after a week's
absence.
</p>

<p>
<q>No better!</q> he groaned. <q>I still have
pains. But they seem to have moved and
scattered all over me.</q>
</p>

<p>
<q>Good!</q> she exclaimed with a smile.
<q>You <hi rend="font-style: italic">are</hi> much better, though you didn't
know it. The wishbone is broken. You
broke it by flying against the trees. And
you ought not to have any more trouble.
But let me examine you!</q> she said, prodding
him in the waistcoat once more.
</p>


<pb n="057" /><anchor id="Pg057" />

<p>
<q>This is odd!</q> she continued a bit later.
<q>I can feel the wishbone more plainly
than ever.</q>
</p>

<p>
<q>That's my own wishbone!</q> Solomon
cried indignantly. <q>I've grown so thin
through not eating that it's a wonder you
can't feel my backbone, too.</q>
</p>

<p>
Aunt Polly Woodchuck looked surprised.
</p>

<p>
<q>Perhaps you're right!</q> said she. <q>Not
having a wishbone of my own, I forgot
that you had one.</q>
</p>

<p>
A look of disgust came over Solomon
Owl's face.
</p>

<p>
<q>You're a very poor doctor,</q> he told
her. <q>Here you've kept me from eating
for a whole week&mdash;and I don't believe it
was necessary at all!</q>
</p>

<p>
<q>Well, you're better, aren't you?</q> she
asked him.
</p>

<pb n="058" /><anchor id="Pg058" />
<p>
<q>I shall be as soon as I have a good
meal,</q> replied Solomon Owl, hopefully.
</p>

<p>
<q>You ought not to eat anything for another
week,</q> Aunt Polly told him solemnly.
</p>

<p>
<q>Nonsense!</q> he cried.
</p>

<p>
<q>I'm a doctor; and I ought to know
best,</q> she insisted.
</p>

<p>
But Solomon Owl hooted rudely.
</p>

<p>
<q>I'll never come to you for advice any
more,</q> he declared. <q>I firmly believe
that my whole trouble was simply that I've
been eating too sparingly. And I shall
take good care to see that it doesn't happen
again.</q>
</p>

<p>
No one had ever spoken to Aunt Polly
in quite that fashion&mdash;though old Mr.
Crow had complained one time that she
had cured him <hi rend="font-style: italic">too quickly</hi>. But she did
not lose her temper, in spite of Solomon's
jeers.
</p>

<pb n="059" /><anchor id="Pg059" />
<p>
<q>You'll be back here again the very
next time you're ill,</q> she remarked.
<q>And if you continue to swallow your
food whole&qdash;</q>
</p>

<p>
But Solomon Owl did not even wait to
hear what she said. He was so impolite
that he flew away while she was talking.
And since it was then almost dark, and a
good time to look for field mice, he began
his night's hunting right there in Farmer
Green's pasture.
</p>

<p>
By morning Solomon was so plump that
Aunt Polly Woodchuck would have had
a good deal of trouble finding his wishbone.
But since he did not visit her again,
she had no further chance to prod him in
the waistcoat.
</p>

<p>
Afterward, Solomon heard a bit of gossip
that annoyed him. A friend of his
reported that Aunt Polly Woodchuck was
going about and telling everybody how she
had saved Solomon's life.
</p>


<pb n="060" /><anchor id="Pg060" />

<p>
<q>Mice!</q> he exclaimed (he often said
that when some would have said <q>Rats!</q>).
<q>There's not a word of truth in her claim.
And if people in this neighborhood keep
on taking her advice and her catnip tea
they're going to be sorry some day. For
they'll be really ill the first thing they
know. And then what will they do?</q>
</p>


<pb n="061" /><anchor id="Pg061" />
</div>

<div rend="page-break-before: always">
<index index="toc" level1="XII - Benjamin Bat" />
<index index="pdf" level1="XII - Benjamin Bat" />
<head>XII<lb />
Benjamin Bat</head>

<p>
Solomon Owl was by no means the only
night-prowler in Pleasant Valley. He had
neighbors that chose to sleep in the daytime,
so they might roam through the
woods and fields after dark. One of these
was Benjamin Bat. And furthermore, he
was the color of night itself.
</p>

<pb n="062" /><anchor id="Pg062" />
<p>
Now, Benjamin Bat was an odd chap.
When he was still he liked to hang by his
feet, upside down. And when he was flying
he sailed about in a zigzag, helter-skelter
fashion. He went in so many different
directions, turning this way and that, one
could never tell where he was going. One
might say that his life was just one continual
dodge&mdash;when he wasn't resting
with his heels where his head ought to be.
</p>

<p>
A good many of Benjamin Bat's friends
said he certainly must be crazy, because
he didn't do as they did. But that never
made the slightest difference in Benjamin
Bat's habits. He continued to zigzag
through life&mdash;and hang by his heels&mdash;just
the same. Perhaps he thought that all
other people were crazy because they
didn't do likewise.
</p>

<p>
Benjamin often dodged across Solomon
Owl's path, when Solomon was hunting
for field mice. And since Benjamin was
the least bit like a mouse himself&mdash;except
for his wings&mdash;there was a time, once,
when Solomon tried to catch him.
</p>

<p>
But Solomon Owl soon found that chasing
Benjamin Bat made him dizzy. If
Benjamin hadn't been used to hanging
head downward, maybe he would have
been dizzy, too.
</p>
<pb n="063" /><anchor id="Pg063" />

<p>
Though the two often saw each other,
Benjamin Bat never seemed to care to
stop for a chat with Solomon Owl. One
night, however, Benjamin actually called
to Solomon and asked his advice. He was
in trouble. And he knew that Solomon
Owl was supposed by some to be the wisest
old fellow for miles around.
</p>

<p>
It was almost morning. And Solomon
Owl was hurrying home, because a terrible
storm had arisen. The lightning was
flashing, and peals of thunder crashed
through the woods. Big drops of rain
were already pattering down. But Solomon
Owl did not care, for he had almost
reached his house in the hollow hemlock
near the foot of Blue Mountain.
</p>

<pb n="064" /><anchor id="Pg064" />
<p>
It was different with Benjamin Bat.
That night he had strayed a long distance
from his home in Cedar Swamp. And
he didn't know what to do. <q>I want to get
under cover, somewhere,</q> he told Solomon
Owl. <q>You don't know of a good place
near-by, do you, where I can get out of the
storm and take a nap?</q>
</p>

<p>
<q>Why, yes!</q> answered Solomon Owl.
<q>Come right along to my house and spend
the day with me!</q>    
</p>

<p>
But Benjamin Bat did not like the suggestion
at all.
</p>

<p>
<q>I'm afraid I might crowd, you,</q> he
said. He was thinking of the time when
Solomon Owl had chased him. And sleeping
in Solomon Owl's house seemed far
from a safe thing to do.
</p>

<p rend="text-align: center"><anchor id="image-002" />
<figure rend="w95" url="images/image-002.jpg">
<head rend="text-align: center">Benjamin Asked Solomon's Advice
</head>
<figDesc><hi rend="font-style: italic">Illustration 2</hi></figDesc>
</figure></p><p></p>
        
<p>
Solomon was wise enough to guess what
was going on inside Benjamin's head.
</p>

<pb n="065" /><anchor id="Pg065" />
<p>
<q>Come along!</q> he said. <q>We'll both be
asleep before we know it. I'm sorry I
can't offer you something to eat. But I
haven't a morsel of food in my house. No
doubt, though, you've just had a good
meal. <hi rend="font-style: italic">I</hi> ate seven mice to-night. And I
certainly couldn't eat anything more.</q>
</p>
   
<p>
When Solomon Owl told him that, Benjamin
Bat thought perhaps there was no
danger, after all. And since the rain was
falling harder and harder every moment,
he thanked Solomon and said he would be
glad to accent his invitation.
</p>

<p>
<q>Follow me, then!</q> said Solomon Owl.
And he led the way to his home in the hemlock.
</p>

<p>
For once, Benjamin Bat flew in a fairly
straight line, though he did a little dodging,
because he couldn't help it.
</p>

<p>
There was more room inside Solomon's
house than Benjamin Bat had supposed.
While Benjamin was looking about and
telling Solomon that he had a fine home,
his host quickly made a bed of leaves in
one corner of the room&mdash;there was only
one room, of course.
</p>
<pb n="066" /><anchor id="Pg066" />

<p>
<q>That's for you!</q> said Solomon Owl.
<q>I always sleep on the other side of the
house.</q> And without waiting even to
make sure that his guest was comfortable,
Solomon Owl lay down and began to snore&mdash;for
he was very sleepy.
</p>

<p>
It was so cozy there that Benjamin Bat
was glad, already, that he had accepted
Solomon's invitation.
</p>


<pb n="067" /><anchor id="Pg067" />
</div>

<div rend="page-break-before: always">
<index index="toc" level1="XIII - The Lucky Guest" />
<index index="pdf" level1="XIII - The Lucky Guest" />
<head>XIII<lb />
The Lucky Guest</head>

<p>
In the middle of the day Solomon Owl
happened to awake. He was sorry that he
hadn't slept until sunset, because he was
very hungry. Knowing that it was light
outside his hollow tree, he didn't want to
leave home to find something to eat.
</p>

<p>
Then, suddenly, he remembered that he
had brought Benjamin Bat to his house
early that morning, so Benjamin might
escape the storm.... Why not eat Benjamin
Bat?
</p>

<p>
As soon as the thought occurred to him,
Solomon Owl liked it. And he moved
stealthily over to the bed of leaves he had
made for his guest just before daybreak.
</p>
<pb n="068" /><anchor id="Pg068" />

<p>
But Benjamin Bat was not there.
Though Solomon looked in every nook and
cranny of his one-room house, he did not
find him.
</p>

<p>
<q>He must have left as soon as it stopped
raining,</q> said Solomon Owl to himself.
<q>He might at least have waited to thank
me for giving him a day's lodging. It's
the last time I'll ever bring any worthless
vagabond into my house. And I ought to
have known better than to have anything
to do with a crazy person like Benjamin
Bat.</q>
</p>

<p>
Anybody can see that Solomon Owl was
displeased. But it was not at all astonishing,
if one stops to remember how hungry
he was, and that he had expected to enjoy
a good meal without the trouble of going
away from home to get it.
</p>

<pb n="069" /><anchor id="Pg069" />
<p>
Solomon Owl went to the door of his
house and looked out. The sun was shining
so brightly that after blinking in his
doorway for a few minutes he decided that
he would go to bed again and try to sleep
until dusk. He never liked bright days.
<q>They're so dismal!</q> he used to say.
<q>Give me a good, dark night and I'm
happy, for there's nothing more cheering
than gloom.</q>
</p>

<p>
In spite of the pangs of hunger that
gnawed inside him, Solomon at last succeeded
in falling asleep once more. And
he dreamed that he chased Benjamin Bat
three times around Blue Mountain, and
then three times back again, in the opposite
direction. But he never could catch
him, because Benjamin Bat simply
wouldn't fly straight. His zigzag course
was so confusing that even in his dream
Solomon Owl grew dizzy.
</p>

<pb n="070" /><anchor id="Pg070" />
<p>
Now, Benjamin Bat was in Solomon's
house all the time. And the reason why
Solomon Owl hadn't found him was a very
simple one. It was merely that Solomon
hadn't looked in the right place.
</p>

<p>
Benjamin Bat was hidden&mdash;as you
might say&mdash;where his hungry host never
once thought of looking for him. And
being asleep all the while, Benjamin didn't
once move or make the slightest noise.
</p>

<p>
If he had snored, or sneezed, or rustled
his wings, no doubt Solomon Owl would
have found him.
</p>

<p>
When Benjamin awakened, late in the
afternoon, Solomon was still sleeping.
And Benjamin crept through the door and
went out into the gathering twilight, without
arousing Solomon.
</p>

<p>
<q>I'll thank him the next time I meet
him,</q> Benjamin Bat decided. And he
staggered away through the air as if he did
not quite know, himself, where he was going. 
But, of course, that was only his
queer way of flying.
</p>
<pb n="071" /><anchor id="Pg071" />

<p>
When he told his friends where he had
spent the day they were astonished.
</p>

<p>
<q>How did you ever dare do anything so
dangerous as sleeping in Solomon Owl's
house?</q> they all asked him.
</p>

<p>
But Benjamin Bat only said, <q>Oh!
There was nothing to be afraid of.</q> And
he began to feel quite important.
</p>


<pb n="072" /><anchor id="Pg072" />
</div>

<div rend="page-break-before: always">
<index index="toc" level1="XIV - Hanging By The Heels" />
<index index="pdf" level1="XIV - Hanging By The Heels" />
<head>XIV<lb />
Hanging By The Heels</head>

<p>
It was several nights before Solomon Owl
and Benjamin Bat chanced to meet again
in the forest.
</p>

<p>
<q>Hullo!</q> said Solomon.
</p>

<p>
<q>Hullo!</q> said Benjamin Bat. <q>I'm
glad to see you, because I want to thank
you for letting me spend the day in your
house, so I wouldn't have to stay out in
the storm.</q>
</p>

<p>
<q>You must be a light sleeper,</q> Solomon
observed. (He did not tell Benjamin
that he was welcome!)
</p>

<p>
<q>What makes you think that?</q> Benjamin
Bat inquired.
</p>


<pb n="073" /><anchor id="Pg073" />

<p>
<q>Why&mdash;you left my house before
noon,</q> Solomon told him.
</p>

<p>
<q>Oh, no!</q> said Benjamin. <q>I slept
soundly until sunset. When I came away
the crickets were chirping. And I was
surprised that you hadn't waked up yourself.</q>
</p>

<p>
<q>You were gone before midday,</q> Solomon
Owl insisted. And they had something
very like a dispute, while Solomon
Owl sat in one tree and Benjamin Bat
hung head downward from another. <q>I
ought to know,</q> said Solomon. <q>I was
awake about noon; and I looked everywhere
for you.</q>
</p>

<p>
<q>What for?</q> asked Benjamin.
</p>

<p>
Naturally, Solomon didn't like to tell
him that he had intended to eat him. So
he looked wise&mdash;and said nothing.
</p>

<p>
<q>You didn't look on the ceiling, did
you?</q> Benjamin Bat inquired.
</p>


<pb n="074" /><anchor id="Pg074" />

<p>
<q>No, indeed!</q> Solomon Owl exclaimed.
</p>

<p>
<q>Well, that's where I was, hanging by
my feet,</q> Benjamin Bat informed him.
</p>

<p>
Solomon Owl certainly was surprised
to hear that.
</p>

<p>
<q>The idea!</q> he cried. <q>You're a queer
one! I never once thought of looking <hi rend="font-style: italic">on
the ceiling</hi> for a <hi rend="font-style: italic">luncheon</hi>!</q> He was so
astonished that he spoke before he thought
how oddly his remark would sound to another.
</p>

<p>
When he heard what Solomon Owl said,
Benjamin Bat knew at once that Solomon
had meant to eat him. And he was so
frightened that he dropped from the limb
to which he was clinging and flew off as
fast as he could go. For once in his life
he flew in a straight line, with no zigzags
at all, he was in such a hurry to get away
from Solomon Owl, who&mdash;for all he knew&mdash;might
still be very hungry.
</p>


<pb n="075" /><anchor id="Pg075" />

<p>
But Solomon Owl had caught so many
mice that night that he didn't feel like
chasing anybody. So he sat motionless in
the tree, merely turning his head to watch
Benjamin sailing away through the dusky
woods. He noticed that Benjamin didn't
dodge at all&mdash;except when there was a tree
in his way. And he wondered what the
reason was.
</p>

<p>
<q>Perhaps he's not so crazy as I supposed,</q>
said Solomon Owl to himself.
And ever afterward, when he happened
to awake and feel hungry, Solomon Owl
used to look up at the ceiling above him
and wish that Benjamin Bat was there.
</p>

<p>
But Benjamin Bat never cared to have
anything more to do with Solomon Owl.
</p>

<p>
He said he had a good reason for avoiding
him.
</p>

<pb n="076" /><anchor id="Pg076" />
<p>
And ever afterward he passed for a very
brave person among his friends. They
often pointed him out to strangers, saying,
<q>There's Benjamin Bat! <hi rend="font-style: italic">He</hi> doesn't
know what fear is. Why, once he even
spent a whole day asleep in Solomon Owl's
house! And if you don't think <hi rend="font-style: italic">that</hi> was a
bold thing to do, then I guess you don't
know Solomon Owl.</q>
</p>

<pb n="077" /><anchor id="Pg077" />
</div>

<div rend="page-break-before: always">
<index index="toc" level1="XV - Disputes Settled" />
<index index="pdf" level1="XV - Disputes Settled" />
<head>XV<lb />
Disputes Settled</head>

<p>
Solomon Owl looked so wise that many
of his neighbors fell into the habit of going
to him for advice. If two of the forest
folk chanced to have a dispute which
they could not settle between them they
frequently visited Solomon and asked him
to decide which was in the right. And in
the course of time Solomon became known
far and wide for his ability to patch up a
quarrel.
</p>

<p>
At last Jimmy Rabbit stopped Solomon
Owl one night and suggested that he hang
a sign outside his house, so that there
shouldn't be anybody in the whole valley
that wouldn't know what to do in case he
found himself in an argument.
</p>
<pb n="078" /><anchor id="Pg078" />

<p>
Solomon decided on the spot that Jimmy
Rabbit's idea was a good one. So he
hurried home and before morning he had
his sign made, and put out where everyone
could see it. It looked like this:
</p>

<p>
DISPUTES SETTLED WITHIN
</p>

<p>
There was only one objection to the
sign. As soon as Jimmy Rabbit saw it he
told Solomon that it should have said:
</p>

<p>
DISPUTES SETTLED WITHOUT
</p>

<p>
<q>Without what?</q> Solomon Owl inquired.
</p>

<pb n="079" /><anchor id="Pg079" />
<p>
<q>Why, without going into your house!</q>
said Jimmy Rabbit. <q>I can't climb a tree,
you know. And neither can Tommy Fox.
We might have a dispute to-night; and
how could you ever settle it?</q>
</p>

<p>
<q>Oh, I shall be willing to step outside,</q>
Solomon told him. And he refused to
change the sign, declaring that he liked it
just as it was.
</p>

<p>
Now, there was only one trouble with
Solomon Owl's settling of disputes.
Many of the forest folk wanted to see him
in the daytime. And <hi rend="font-style: italic">night</hi> was the only
time <hi rend="font-style: italic">he</hi> was willing to see them. But he
heard so many objections to that arrangement
that in the end Solomon agreed to
meet people at dusk and at dawn, when it
was neither very dark nor very light. On
the whole he found that way very satisfactory,
because there was just enough
light at dusk and at dawn to make him
blink. And when Solomon blinked he
looked even wiser than ever.
</p>

<pb n="080" /><anchor id="Pg080" />
<p>
Well, the first disputing pair that came
to Solomon's tree after he hung out his
new sign were old Mr. Crow and Jasper
Jay. They reached the hemlock grove
soon after sunset and squalled loudly for
Solomon. <q>Hurry!</q> Mr. Crow cried, as
soon as Solomon Owl stepped outside his
door. <q>It will be dark before we know it;
and it's almost our bedtime.</q>
</p>

<p>
<q>What's your difficulty?</q> Solomon
asked them.
</p>

<p>
Mr. Crow looked at Jasper Jay. And
then he looked at Solomon again.
</p>

<p>
<q>Maybe you won't like to hear it,</q> he
said. And he winked at Jasper. <q>But
you've put out this sign&mdash;so we've come
here.</q>
</p>

<p>
<q>You've done just right!</q> exclaimed
Solomon Owl. <q>And as for my not liking
to hear the trouble, it's your dispute and
not mine. So I don't see how it concerns
me&mdash;except to settle it.</q>
</p>


<pb n="081" /><anchor id="Pg081" />

<p>
<q>Very Well,</q> Mr. Crow answered.
<q>The dispute, then, is this: Jasper says
that in spite of your looking so wise,
you're really the stupidest person in
Pleasant Valley.</q>
</p>

<p>
<q>He does, eh?</q> cried Solomon Owl,
while Jasper Jay laughed loudly. <q>And
you, of course, do not agree with him,</q>
Solomon continued.
</p>

<p>
<q>I do not!</q> Mr. Crow declared.
</p>

<p>
<q>Good!</q> said Solomon, nodding his
head approvingly.
</p>

<p>
<q>No, I do not agree with Jasper Jay,</q>
Mr. Crow said. <q>I claim that there's one
other person more stupid than you are&mdash;and
that's Fatty Coon.</q>
</p>

<p>
Well, Solomon Owl certainly was displeased.
And it didn't make him feel any
happier to hear Jasper Jay's boisterous
shouts, or the hoarse <q><hi rend="font-style: italic">haw-haw</hi></q> of old
Mr. Crow.
</p>


<pb n="082" /><anchor id="Pg082" />

<p>
<q>I hope you can decide which one of us
is right,</q> Mr. Crow ventured.
</p>

<p>
<q>I am, of course!</q> cried Jasper Jay.
</p>

<p>
<q>You're not!</q> Mr. Crow shouted. And
to Solomon Owl he said, <q>We've been disputing
like this all day long.</q>
</p>

<p>
Solomon Owl didn't know what to say.
If he announced that Jasper was right it
would be the same as admitting that he
was the stupidest person in the whole
neighborhood. And if he said that old
Mr. Crow's opinion was correct he would
not be much better off. Naturally he
didn't want to tell either of them that he
was right.
</p>

<p>
<q>I'll have to think about this,</q> Solomon
observed at last.
</p>

<p>
<q>We don't want to wait,</q> said Mr.
Crow. <q>If we keep on disputing we're
likely to have a fight.</q>
</p>

<pb n="083" /><anchor id="Pg083" />
<p>
Now, Solomon Owl hoped that they
would have a fight. So he was determined
to keep them waiting for his decision.
</p>

<p>
<q>Come back to-morrow at this time,</q>
he said.
</p>


<pb n="084" /><anchor id="Pg084" />
</div>

<div rend="page-break-before: always">
<index index="toc" level1="XVI - Nine Fights" />
<index index="pdf" level1="XVI - Nine Fights" />
<head>XVI<lb />
Nine Fights</head>

<p>
The next evening, just at dusk, Jasper
Jay and old Mr. Crow returned to Solomon
Owl's house, looking much bedraggled.
One of Mr. Crow's eyes was almost
closed; and Jasper Jay's crest seemed to
have been torn half off his head.
</p>

<p>
<q>What's the matter?</q> asked Solomon,
as soon as he saw them.
</p>

<p>
<q>We've had three fights,</q> said Jasper
Jay.
</p>

<p>
<q>Yes! And I've whipped him each
time!</q> cried Mr. Crow. <q>So I must be in
the right. And you'd better decide our
dispute in my favor at once.</q>
</p>


<pb n="085" /><anchor id="Pg085" />

<p>
But Solomon Owl was still in no hurry.
</p>

<p>
<q>It's a difficult question to settle,<q> said
he. </q>I don't want to make any mistake.
So I shall have to ask you to come back
here to-morrow at this time.</q>
</p>

<p>
Both Jasper and Mr. Crow seemed disappointed.
Although Mr. Crow had won
each fight, he was very weary, for he was
older than Jasper Jay.
</p>

<p>
As they went off, Solomon Owl began
to feel much pleased with himself.
</p>

<p>
The following evening, at sunset, old
Mr. Crow and Jasper Jay visited Solomon
Owl once more. And they looked
more battered than ever.
</p>

<p>
<q>We've had three more fights,</q> said
Mr. Crow.
</p>

<p>
<q>Yes! And I won each time!</q> Jasper
Jay piped up. <q>So I must be in the right.
And you'd better decide in my favor without
any further delay.</q>
</p>


<pb n="086" /><anchor id="Pg086" />

<p>
Solomon Owl thought deeply for some
time.
</p>

<p>
<q>Maybe I ought to wait until to-morrow&qdash;</q>
he began.
</p>

<p>
But his callers both shouted <q>No!</q>
</p>

<p>
<q>Well,</q> said Solomon, <q>Mr. Crow has
won three fights; and Jasper Jay has won
three. So it is certain that each must be
in the wrong.</q>
</p>

<p>
But that announcement did not satisfy
Jasper and Mr. Crow. And they left the
hemlock grove, disputing more loudly than
ever.
</p>

<p>
And the next day, at dusk, they came
back again.
</p>

<p>
<q>We've had three more fights; and I
won!</q> they both cried at the same time.
</p>

<p>
<q>That proves my claim,</q> said Solomon
Owl. <q>You're both wrong.</q>
</p>

<p>
They whispered together for a few minutes.
</p>


<pb n="087" /><anchor id="Pg087" />

<p>
<q>We don't like your way of settling disputes,</q>
Mr. Crow remarked shortly. <q>But
we've decided to stop quarreling.</q>
</p>

<p>
<q>Good!</q> said Solomon Owl. <q>That
shows that you are sensible.</q>
</p>

<p>
<q>Yes!</q> replied Jasper. <q>We've decided
to stop quarreling and fight <hi rend="font-style: italic">you</hi>!</q>
</p>

<p>
<q>Wait a moment!</q> said Solomon Owl
hastily, as they drew nearer. <q>I don't
want my new suit spoiled.</q> And he
ducked inside the hollow tree before they
could reach him.
</p>

<p>
Jasper and Mr. Crow waited and
waited. But Solomon Owl did not reappear.
And since his two visitors did not
dare follow him into the dark cavern
where he lived, they decided at last that
they would go home&mdash;and get into bed.
</p>

<p>
<q>Let's take away his sign, anyhow!</q>
Jasper Jay suggested.
</p>

<pb n="088" /><anchor id="Pg088" />
<p>
So they pulled down Solomon's sign,
which said <q>Disputes Settled Within,</q>
and they carried it off with them and hid
it in some bushes.
</p>

<p>
That same night Solomon Owl hunted
for it for a long time. But he never found
it.
</p>

<p>
He decided not to hang out another,
for he saw that settling disputes was a
dangerous business.
</p>


<pb n="089" /><anchor id="Pg089" />
</div>

<div rend="page-break-before: always">
<index index="toc" level1="XVII - Cousin Simon Screecher" />
<index index="pdf" level1="XVII - Cousin Simon Screecher" />
<head>XVII<lb />
Cousin Simon Screecher</head>

<p>
Solomon Owl had a small cousin named
Simon Screecher. He was unlike Solomon
in some respects, because he always
wore ear-tufts, and his eyes were yellow
instead of black. But in some other ways
he was no different from Solomon Owl, for
he was a noisy chap and dearly loved mice&mdash;to
eat.
</p>

<p>
It happened that the two met in the
woods one fine fall evening; and they
agreed to go hunting mice together.
</p>

<pb n="090" /><anchor id="Pg090" />
<p>
Now, being so much smaller than Solomon,
Simon Screecher was all the spryer.
In fact, he was so active that he could
catch mice faster than Solomon Owl could
capture them. And they had not hunted
long before Solomon discovered that
Simon had succeeded in disposing of six
mice to his three.
</p>

<p>
That discovery did not please Solomon
at all.
</p>

<p>
<q>Look here!</q> he said. <q>Since we are
hunting together it's only fair to divide
what we catch, half and half.</q>
</p>

<p>
Simon Screecher hesitated. But after
reflecting that his cousin was very big and
very strong, he agreed to Solomon's suggestion.
</p>

<p>
So they resumed their hunting. And
every time one of them caught two mice,
he gave one mouse to his cousin.
</p>

<p>
Still Solomon Owl was not satisfied.
</p>

<pb n="091" /><anchor id="Pg091" />
<p>
<q>Wait a moment!</q> Solomon called to
Simon Screecher. <q>It has just occurred
to me that I am more than twice as big
as you are; so I ought to have twice as
many mice as you.</q>
</p>

<p>
This time Simon Screecher hesitated
longer. He did not like the second suggestion
even as well as the first. And in
the end he said as much, too.
</p>

<p>
But Solomon Owl insisted that it was
only fair.
</p>

<p>
<q>You surely ought to be glad to please
your own cousin,</q> he told Simon.
</p>

<p>
<q>It's not that,</q> said Simon Screecher.
<q>It seems to me that since I'm not half
your size, I ought to have twice as many
mice to eat, so I'll grow bigger.</q>
</p>

<p>
Well, Solomon Owl hadn't thought of
that. He was puzzled to know what to
say. And he wanted time in which to
ponder.
</p>

<pb n="092" /><anchor id="Pg092" />
<p>
<q>I'll think over what you say,</q> he told
Simon Screecher. <q>And now, since it's
almost dawn, we'd better not hunt any
longer to-night. But I'll meet you again
at dusk if you'll come to my house.</q>
</p>

<p>
<q>Very well, Cousin Solomon!</q> Simon
answered. <q>I'm sure that after you've
had a good sleep you'll be ready to agree
with me.</q>
</p>

<p>
<q>If that's the case, I may not take any
nap at all,</q> Solomon replied.
</p>

<p>
<q>Oh! You ought to have your rest!</q>
his cousin exclaimed. Simon knew that if
Solomon went all day without sleep he
would be frightfully peevish by nightfall.
</p>

<p>
<q>Well&mdash;I'll try to get forty winks,</q>
Solomon promised. <q>But I don't believe
I can get more than that, because I have
so much on my mind that I'm sure to be
wakeful.</q>
</p>

<pb n="093" /><anchor id="Pg093" />
<p>
Simon Screecher was somewhat worried
as they parted. His wailing, tremulous
whistle, which floated through the shadowy 
woods, showed that he was far from
happy.
</p>


<pb n="094" /><anchor id="Pg094" />
</div>

<div rend="page-break-before: always">
<index index="toc" level1="XVIII - A Cousinly Quarrel" />
<index index="pdf" level1="XVIII - A Cousinly Quarrel" />
<head>XVIII<lb />
XVIII - A Cousinly Quarrel</head>

<p>
It proved to be just as Solomon Owl had
told his cousin, Simon Screecher. Solomon
had so much on his mind that he had
no sooner fallen asleep than he awoke
again, to study over the question that perplexed
him. He certainly did not want
Simon to have twice as many mice as he.
But Simon's argument was a good one.
He had said that since Solomon was more
than twice his size, it was proper that he
should have a chance to grow. And everybody
knew&mdash;Solomon reflected&mdash;everybody
knew that <hi rend="font-style: italic">eating</hi> made one larger.
</p>

<pb n="095" /><anchor id="Pg095" />
<p>
The longer Solomon pondered, the farther 
he seemed from any answer that he
liked. And he had begun to fear that he
would not succeed in getting more than
thirty-nine winks all day&mdash;instead of
forty&mdash;when all at once an idea came into
his mind.
</p>

<p>
Solomon knew right away that he had
nothing more to worry about. He dropped
into a sound sleep with a pleasant smile
upon his usually solemn face. And when
he opened his eyes again it was time for
Simon Screecher to arrive.
</p>

<p>
Yes! Solomon could hear his cousin's
whistle even then. So he hurried to his
door; and there was Simon, sitting on a
limb of the big hemlock waiting for him!
</p>

<p>
<q>It's all right!</q> said Solomon to his
cousin. <q>I agree to your suggestion.
We'll hunt together again to-night; and if
you will give me one-third of all the mice
you catch, I promise to give you two-thirds 
of all the mice that I capture.</q>
</p>
<pb n="096" /><anchor id="Pg096" />

<p>
<q>Good!</q> said Simon Screecher. And
he looked vastly relieved. <q>Just hoot
when you have any mice for me!</q>
</p>

<p>
<q>Whistle when you have any for me!</q>
Solomon Owl replied.
</p>

<p>
And at that they started out for their
night's sport. It was not long before
Simon Screecher's well known whistle
brought Solomon hurrying to him. Simon
already had three mice, one of which he
gave to Solomon, according to their agreement.
</p>

<p>
That same thing happened several
times; until at last Simon Screecher began
to grumble.
</p>

<p>
<q>What's the matter?</q> he asked his
cousin. <q>You are not hooting, as you
promised you would.</q>
</p>

<p>
<q>But I haven't caught any mice yet!</q>
Solomon Owl replied.
</p>

<p rend="text-align: center"><anchor id="image-003" />
<figure rend="w95" url="images/image-003.jpg">
<head rend="text-align: center"><q>It's All Right,</q> Said Solomon
</head>
<figDesc><hi rend="font-style: italic">Illustration 3</hi></figDesc>
</figure></p><p></p>

<pb n="097" /><anchor id="Pg097" />

<p>
Again and again and again Simon's
call summoned Solomon. But not once
did Solomon's summon Simon. And all
the time Simon Screecher grew more discontented.
Toward the end of the night
he declared flatly that he wasn't going to
hunt any more with his cousin.
</p>

<p>
<q>I've done exactly as I agreed!</q> Solomon
Owl protested.
</p>

<p>
<q>You're altogether too slow and
clumsy,</q> Simon Screecher told him bluntly.
<q>If I'm going to hunt with anybody
after this I'm going to choose someone
that's as spry as I am. There's no sense
in my working for you. Here I've toiled
all night long and I'm still hungry, for
I've given you a third of my food.</q>
</p>

<p>
They parted then&mdash;and none too pleasantly.
</p>

<pb n="098" /><anchor id="Pg098" />
<p>
In Simon's whistle, as he flew away toward
his home, there was unmistakable
anger. But Solomon Owl's answering
hoots&mdash;while they were not exactly sweet&mdash;seemed
to carry more than a hint of
laughter.
</p>

<p>
One would naturally think that Solomon
might have been even hungrier than
his small cousin. But it was not so. He
had had more to eat than usual; for he had
been very busy catching locusts and katydids&mdash;and
frogs, too. Solomon Owl had
not tried to catch a single mouse that
night.
</p>

<p>
You know now the idea that had come
to him while he was lying awake in his
house during the daytime. He had made
up his mind that he would not hunt for
<hi rend="font-style: italic">mice</hi>. And since he had not promised
Simon to give him anything else, there was
no reason why he should not eat all the
frogs and katydids and locusts that he
could find.
</p>


<pb n="099" /><anchor id="Pg099" />

<p>
Perhaps it was not surprising that
Simon Screecher never guessed the truth.
But he seemed to know that there was
something queer about that night's hunting,
for he never came to Solomon Owl's
house again.
</p>


<pb n="100" /><anchor id="Pg100" />
</div>

<div rend="page-break-before: always">
<index index="toc" level1="XIX - The Sleet Storm" />
<index index="pdf" level1="XIX - The Sleet Storm" />
<head>XIX<lb />
The Sleet Storm</head>

<p>
It was winter. And for several days a
strong south wind had swept up Pleasant
Valley. That&mdash;as Solomon Owl knew
very well&mdash;that meant a thaw was coming.
He was not sorry, because the weather had
been bitterly cold.
</p>

<p>
Well, the thaw came. And the weather
grew so warm that Solomon Owl could
stay out all night without once feeling
chilled. He found the change so agreeable
that he strayed further from home
than was his custom. Indeed, he was far
away on the other side of Blue Mountain
at midnight, when it began to rain.
</p>


<pb n="101" /><anchor id="Pg101" />

<p>
Now, that was not quite so pleasant.
But still Solomon did not mind greatly. It
was not until later that he began to feel
alarmed, when he noticed that flying did
not seem so easy as usual.
</p>

<p>
Solomon had grown heavy all at once&mdash;and
goodness knows it was not because he
had overeaten, for food was scarce at that
season of the year. Moreover, Solomon's
wings were strangely stiff. When he
moved them they <hi rend="font-style: italic">crackled</hi>.
</p>

<p>
<q>It must be my joints,</q> he said to himself.
<q>I'm afraid this wetting has given
me rheumatism.</q> So he started home at
once&mdash;though it was only midnight. But
the further he went, the worse he felt&mdash;and
the harder it was to fly.
</p>

<p>
<q>I'll have to rest a while,</q> he said to
himself at last. So he alighted on a limb;
for he was more tired than he had ever
been in all his life.
</p>


<pb n="102" /><anchor id="Pg102" />

<p>
But he soon felt so much better that he
was ready to start on again. And then,
to his dismay, Solomon Owl found that he
could hardly stir. The moment he left
his perch he floundered down upon the
ground. And though he tried his hardest,
he couldn't reach the tree again.
</p>

<p>
The rain was still beating down steadily.
And Solomon began to think it a bad
night to be out. What was worse, the
weather was fast turning cold.
</p>

<p>
<q>I'm afraid I'll have to stay in bed a
week after this,</q> he groaned. <q>If I sit
here long, as wet as I am, while the thaw
turns into a <hi rend="font-style: italic">freeze</hi>, I shall certainly be ill.</q>
</p>

<p>
Now, if it hadn't been for the rain, Solomon
Owl would have had no trouble at all.
Or if it hadn't been for the freezing cold
he would have been in no difficulty.
Though he didn't know it, his trouble was
simply this: The rain froze upon him as
</p>


<pb n="103" /><anchor id="Pg103" />

<p>
fast as it fell, covering him with a coating
of ice. It was no wonder that he felt
strangely heavy&mdash;no wonder that he
couldn't fly.
</p>

<p>
There he crouched on the ground, while
the rain and sleet beat upon him. And
the only comforting thought that entered
his head was that on so stormy a night
Tommy Fox and Fatty Coon would be
snug and warm in their beds. <hi rend="font-style: italic">They</hi>
wouldn't go out in such weather.
</p>

<p>
And Solomon Owl wished that he, too,
had stayed at home that night.
</p>

<p>
From midnight until almost dawn Solomon
Owl sat there. Now and then he tried
to fly. But it was no use. He could
scarcely raise himself off the ground.
</p>

<p>
At last he decided he would have to <hi rend="font-style: italic">walk</hi>
home. Fortunately, a hard crust covered
the soft snow. So Solomon started off on
his long journey.
</p>


<pb n="104" /><anchor id="Pg104" />

<p>
Flying, Solomon could have covered the
distance in a few minutes. But he was a
slow walker. By the time he reached his
home among the hemlocks the sun was
shining brightly&mdash;for the rain had stopped
before daybreak.
</p>

<p>
Solomon wondered how he would ever
succeed in reaching his doorway, high up
in the hollow tree. He gazed helplessly
upward. And as he sat there mournfully
the bright sunshine melted the ice that
bound his wings. After a time he discovered
that he could move freely once more.
And then he rose quickly in the air and in
a twinkling he had disappeared into the
darkness of his home&mdash;that darkness
which to him was always so pleasant.
</p>


<pb n="105" /><anchor id="Pg105" />

</div>

<div rend="page-break-before: always">
<index index="toc" level1="XX - A Pair Of Red-Heads" />
<index index="pdf" level1="XX - A Pair Of Red-Heads" />
<head>XX<lb />
A Pair Of Red-Heads</head>

<p>
In the woods there was hardly one of Solomon
Owl's neighbors that couldn't point
out the big hemlock tree where he lived.
And mischievous fellows like Reddy
Woodpecker sometimes annoyed Solomon
a good deal by rapping loudly on his door.
When he thrust his head angrily out of his
house and blinked in the sunlight, his tormentors
would skip away and laugh. They
laughed because they knew that they had
awakened Solomon Owl. And they dodged
out of his reach because he was always ill-tempered
when anybody disturbed his rest
in the daytime.
</p>


<pb n="106" /><anchor id="Pg106" />

<p>
Solomon Owl did not mind so <hi rend="font-style: italic">very</hi> much
so long as that trick was not played on
him too often. But after a time it became
one of Reddy Woodpecker's favorite
sports. Not only once, but several times
a day did he go to the hemlock grove to
hammer upon Solomon's hollow tree. And
each time that he brought Solomon Owl
to his door Reddy Woodpecker laughed
more loudly than ever before.
</p>

<p>
Once Solomon forgot to take off his
nightcap (though he wore it in the daytime,
it really was a nightcap). And Reddy
Woodpecker was so amused that he
shouted at the top of his lungs.
</p>

<p>
<q>What's the joke?</q> asked Solomon Owl
in his deep, rumbling voice. He tried to
look very severe. But it is hard to look
any way except funny with a nightcap on
one's head.
</p>

<pb n="107" /><anchor id="Pg107" />
<p>
As luck had it, Jasper Jay came hurrying 
up just then. He had heard Reddy
Woodpecker's laughter. And if there
was a joke he wanted to enjoy it, too.
</p>

<p>
Jasper Jay, alighting in a small hemlock
near Reddy Woodpecker, asked the
same question that Solomon Owl had just
put to his rude caller.
</p>

<p>
<q>What's the joke?</q> inquired Jasper
Jay.
</p>

<p>
Reddy could not speak. He was rocking
back and forth upon a limb, choking
and gasping for breath. But he managed
to point to the big tree where Solomon Owl
lived.
</p>

<p>
And when Jasper looked, and saw Solomon's
great, round, pale, questioning face,
all tied up in a red nightcap, he began to
scream.
</p>

<pb n="108" /><anchor id="Pg108" />
<p>
They were no ordinary screams&mdash;those
shrieks of Jasper Jay's. That blue-coated
rascal was the noisiest of all the feathered
folk in Pleasant Valley. And now he fairly
made the woods echo with his hoarse
cries.
</p>

<p>
<q>This is the funniest sight I've ever
seen!</q> Jasper Jay said at last, to nobody
in particular. <q>I declare, there's a pair
of them!</q>
</p>

<p>
At that, Reddy Woodpecker suddenly
stopped laughing.
</p>

<p>
<q>A pair of what?</q> he asked.
</p>

<p>
<q>A pair of red-heads, of course!</q> Jasper
Jay replied. <q>You've a red cap&mdash;and
so has he!</q> Jasper pointed at Solomon
Owl (a very rude thing to do!).
</p>

<p>
Then two things happened all at once.
Solomon Owl snatched off his red 
night-cap&mdash;which he had quite forgotten. And
Reddy Woodpecker dashed at Jasper
Jay. He couldn't pull off <hi rend="font-style: italic">his</hi> red cap, for
it grew right on his head.
</p>

<pb n="109" /><anchor id="Pg109" />
<p>
<q>So that's what you're laughing at, is
it?</q> he cried angrily. And then nobody
laughed any more&mdash;that is, nobody but
Solomon Owl.
</p>

<p>
Solomon was so pleased by the fight that
followed between Jasper Jay and Reddy
Woodpecker that his deep, rumbling
laughter could be heard for half an hour&mdash;even
if it <hi rend="font-style: italic">was</hi> midday. <q><hi rend="font-style: italic">Wha-wha!
Whoo-ah!</hi></q> The sound reached the ears
of Farmer Green, who was just crossing
a neighboring field, on his way home to
dinner.
</p>

<p>
<q>Well, well!</q> he exclaimed. <q>I wonder
what's happened to that old owl!
Something must have tickled him&mdash;for I
never heard an owl laugh in broad daylight
before.</q>
</p>


<pb n="110" /><anchor id="Pg110" />
</div>

<div rend="page-break-before: always">
<index index="toc" level1="XXI - At Home In The Haystack" />
<index index="pdf" level1="XXI - At Home In The Haystack" />
<head>XXI<lb />
At Home In The Haystack</head>

<p>
After what happened when he came to
his door without remembering to take off
his red nightcap, Solomon Owl hoped that
Reddy Woodpecker would stop teasing
him.
</p>

<p>
But it was not so. Having once viewed
Solomon's red cap, Reddy Woodpecker
wanted to see it some more. So he came
again and again and knocked on Solomon's
door.
</p>

<pb n="111" /><anchor id="Pg111" />
<p>
Solomon Owl, however, remembered
each time to remove his nightcap before
sticking his head out. And it might be
said that neither of them was exactly
pleased. For Reddy Woodpecker was
disappointed; and Solomon Owl was angry.
</p>

<p>
Not a day passed that Reddy Woodpecker
didn't disturb Solomon's rest at
least a dozen times. Perhaps if Solomon
had just kept still inside his house Reddy
would have grown tired of bothering him.
But Solomon Owl&mdash;for all he looked so
wise&mdash;never thought of that.
</p>

<p>
But he saw before a great while that he
would have to make a change of some
sort&mdash;if he wanted to enjoy a good, quiet
sleep again.
</p>

<p>
For a long time Solomon Owl pondered.
It was a great puzzle&mdash;to know just how to
outwit Reddy Woodpecker. And Solomon
almost despaired of finding a way out
of the difficulty. But at last an idea came
to him, all in a flash. He would take his
daytime naps somewhere else!
</p>


<pb n="112" /><anchor id="Pg112" />

<p>
Solomon spent several nights looking 
for a good place to pass his days. And in
the end he decided on the meadow. It
would be convenient, he thought, when he
was hunting meadow mice at dawn, if he
could stay right there, without bothering
to go into the woods to sleep.
</p>

<p>
Since there were no trees in the
meadow, but only a few scrubby bushes
along the stone wall, one might naturally
make the mistake of thinking that there
could not possibly be a nook of any kind
that would suit Solomon Owl, who could
never sleep soundly unless his bedroom
was quite dark.
</p>

<p>
But there was one hiding place that Solomon
liked almost as well as his home in
the hollow hemlock. And that was Farmer
Green's haystack. He burrowed into one
side of it and made himself a snug chamber,
which was as dark as a pocket&mdash;and
ever so much quieter. What pleased Solomon
most, however, was this: Nobody
knew about that new retreat except himself.
</p>
<pb n="113" /><anchor id="Pg113" />

<p>
Even if Reddy Woodpecker should succeed
in finding it, he never could disturb
Solomon by drumming upon the haystack.
If Reddy tried that trick, his bill would
merely sink noiselessly into the hay.
</p>

<p>
So Solomon Owl at last had a good day's
rest. And when he met Reddy Woodpecker
just after sunset, Solomon was
feeling so cheerful that he said <q>Good-evening!</q>
quite pleasantly, before he remembered
that it was Reddy who had
teased him so often.
</p>

<p>
<q>Good-evening!</q> Reddy Woodpecker
replied. He seemed much surprised that
Solomon Owl should be so agreeable.
<q>Can you hear me?</q> Reddy asked him.
</p>

<p>
<q>Perfectly!</q> said Solomon.
</p>


<pb n="114" /><anchor id="Pg114" />

<p>
<q>That's strange!</q> Reddy Woodpecker
exclaimed. <q>I was almost sure you had
suddenly grown deaf.</q> And he could not
understand why Solomon Owl laughed
loud and long.
</p>

<p>
<q><hi rend="font-style: italic">Wha-wha! Whoo-ah!</hi></q> Solomon's
deep-voiced laughter rolled and echoed
through the woodland.
</p>

<p>
But Reddy Woodpecker did not laugh
at all.
</p>

<pb n="115" /><anchor id="Pg115" />
</div>

<div rend="page-break-before: always">
<index index="toc" level1="XXII - It Was Solomon's Fault" />
<index index="pdf" level1="XXII - It Was Solomon's Fault" />
<head>XXII<lb />
It Was Solomon's Fault</head>

<p>
Reddy Woodpecker had a very good reason
for not laughing when he met Solomon
Owl. Of course, he knew nothing
whatever of Solomon's new hiding place
in the haystack. And that very morning
Reddy had invited a party of friends to
go with him to the hemlock grove where
Solomon Owl had always lived, <q>to have
some fun,</q> as Reddy had explained.
</p>

<p>
For a long time he had knocked and
hammered and pounded at Solomon Owl's
door. But for once Solomon's great pale
face did not appear.
</p>

<pb n="116" /><anchor id="Pg116" />
<p>
<q>Where's the fun?</q> Reddy's friends
had wanted to know, after they had
waited until they were impatient.
</p>

<p>
And Reddy Woodpecker could only
shake his head and say:
</p>

<p>
<q>I can't understand it! It's never happened
like this before. I'm afraid Solomon
Owl has lost his hearing.</q>
</p>

<p>
Reddy Woodpecker's friends were no
more polite than he. And they began to
jeer at him.
</p>

<p>
<q>You didn't hammer loud enough,</q> one
of them told him.
</p>

<p>
So he set to work again and rapped and
rapped until his head felt as if it would
fly off, and his neck began to ache.
</p>

<p>
Still, Solomon Owl did not appear.
And the party broke up in something very
like a quarrel. For Reddy Woodpecker
lost his temper when his friends teased
him; and a good many unpleasant remarks
passed back and forth.
</p>


<pb n="117" /><anchor id="Pg117" />

<p>
Somehow, Reddy felt that it was all Solomon
Owl's fault, because he hadn't come
to the door.
</p>

<p>
Of course, Reddy had no means of
knowing that all that time Solomon Owl
was sleeping peacefully in Farmer
Green's haystack in the meadow, a quarter
of a mile away.
</p>

<p>
It was a good joke on Reddy Woodpecker.
And though no one had told Solomon
Owl about it, he was not so stupid
that he couldn't guess at least <hi rend="font-style: italic">a little</hi> that
had happened.
</p>
<milestone unit="tb" />
<p>
Solomon Owl continued to have a very
pleasant time living in the meadow. Since
there were many mice right close at hand,
little by little he visited the woods less and
less. And there came a time at last when
he hardly left the meadow at all.
</p>

<pb n="118" /><anchor id="Pg118" />
<p>
Not flying any more than he could help,
and eating too much, and sleeping very
soundly each day, he grew stouter than
ever, until his friends hardly knew him
when they saw him.
</p>

<p>
<q>Solomon Owl is a sight&mdash;he's so fat!</q>
people began to say.
</p>

<p>
But his size never worried Solomon Owl
in the least. When he became too big for
his doorway in the haystack, it was a simple
matter to make the opening larger&mdash;much
simpler than it would have been to
make himself <hi rend="font-style: italic">smaller</hi>. And that was another
reason why he was delighted with
his new home.
</p>

<p>
At last, however, something happened
to put an end to his lazy way of living.
One day the sound of men's voices awakened
him, when he was having a good nap
in the haystack. And he felt his bedroom
quiver as if an earthquake had shaken it.
</p>

<pb n="119" /><anchor id="Pg119" />
<p>
Scrambling to his doorway and peeping
slyly out, Solomon saw a sight that made
him very angry. A hayrack stood alongside
the stack; and on it stood Farmer
Green and his hired man. Each had a
pitchfork in his hands, with which he tore
great forkfuls of hay off the stack and
piled it upon the wagon.        
</p>

<p>
Solomon Owl knew then that his fine  
hiding place was going to be spoiled. As
soon as the horses had pulled the load of
hay away, with Farmer Green and the
hired man riding on top of it, Solomon
Owl crept out of his snug bedroom and 
hurried off to the woods.
</p>

<p>
He was so fat that it was several days
before he could squeeze inside his old home
in the hollow hemlock. And for the time
being he had to sit on a limb and sleep  
in the daylight as best he could.
</p>

<pb n="120" /><anchor id="Pg120" />
<p>
But to his surprise, Reddy Woodpecker
troubled him no more.  Reddy had
drummed so hard on Solomon's door, in
the effort to awake him when he wasn't
there, that Aunt Polly Woodchuck told
him he would ruin his bill, if he didn't look
out. And since the warning thoroughly
alarmed him, Reddy stopped visiting the
hemlock grove.
</p>

<p>
In time Solomon Owl grew to look like
himself again. And people never really
knew just what had happened to him. But
they noticed that he always hooted angrily
whenever anybody mentioned Farmer
Green's name.
</p>

<p>
<lb /><lb />
THE END
</p>

</div>

</body>

  <back>
  <div rend="page-break-before: always">
  <divGen type="pgfooter" />
  </div>
  </back>

    </text>
</TEI.2>

<!--
A Word from Project Gutenberg


This file should be named 16663-0.txt or 16663-0.zip.

This and all associated files of various formats will be found in:


      http://www.gutenberg.org/dirs/1/6/6/6/16663/


Updated editions will replace the previous one  the old editions will be
renamed.

Creating the works from public domain print editions means that no one
owns a United States copyright in these works, so the Foundation (and
you!) can copy and distribute it in the United States without permission
and without paying copyright royalties. Special rules, set forth in the
General Terms of Use part of this license, apply to copying and
distributing Project Gutenberg-tm electronic works to protect the Project
Gutenberg-tm concept and trademark. Project Gutenberg is a registered
trademark, and may not be used if you charge for the eBooks, unless you
receive specific permission. If you do not charge anything for copies of
this eBook, complying with the rules is very easy. You may use this eBook
for nearly any purpose such as creation of derivative works, reports,
performances and research. They may be modified and printed and given away
 you may do practically _anything_ with public domain eBooks.
Redistribution is subject to the trademark license, especially commercial
redistribution.




The Full Project Gutenberg License


_Please read this before you distribute or use this work._

To protect the Project Gutenberg-tm mission of promoting the free
distribution of electronic works, by using or distributing this work (or
any other work associated in any way with the phrase Project Gutenberg),
you agree to comply with all the terms of the Full Project Gutenberg-tm
License (available with this file or online
(http://www.gutenberg.org/license)).



Section 1.


  General Terms of Use & Redistributing Project Gutenberg-tm electronic
                                  works


1.A.


By reading or using any part of this Project Gutenberg-tm electronic work,
you indicate that you have read, understand, agree to and accept all the
terms of this license and intellectual property (trademark/copyright)
agreement. If you do not agree to abide by all the terms of this
agreement, you must cease using and return or destroy all copies of
Project Gutenberg-tm electronic works in your possession. If you paid a
fee for obtaining a copy of or access to a Project Gutenberg-tm electronic
work and you do not agree to be bound by the terms of this agreement, you
may obtain a refund from the person or entity to whom you paid the fee as
set forth in paragraph 1.E.8.


1.B.


Project Gutenberg is a registered trademark. It may only be used on or
associated in any way with an electronic work by people who agree to be
bound by the terms of this agreement. There are a few things that you can
do with most Project Gutenberg-tm electronic works even without complying
with the full terms of this agreement. See paragraph 1.C below. There are
a lot of things you can do with Project Gutenberg-tm electronic works if
you follow the terms of this agreement and help preserve free future
access to Project Gutenberg-tm electronic works. See paragraph 1.E below.


1.C.


The Project Gutenberg Literary Archive Foundation (the Foundation or
PGLAF), owns a compilation copyright in the collection of Project
Gutenberg-tm electronic works. Nearly all the individual works in the
collection are in the public domain in the United States. If an individual
work is in the public domain in the United States and you are located in
the United States, we do not claim a right to prevent you from copying,
distributing, performing, displaying or creating derivative works based on
the work as long as all references to Project Gutenberg are removed. Of
course, we hope that you will support the Project Gutenberg-tm mission of
promoting free access to electronic works by freely sharing Project
Gutenberg-tm works in compliance with the terms of this agreement for
keeping the Project Gutenberg-tm name associated with the work. You can
easily comply with the terms of this agreement by keeping this work in the
same format with its attached full Project Gutenberg-tm License when you
share it without charge with others.


1.D.


The copyright laws of the place where you are located also govern what you
can do with this work. Copyright laws in most countries are in a constant
state of change. If you are outside the United States, check the laws of
your country in addition to the terms of this agreement before
downloading, copying, displaying, performing, distributing or creating
derivative works based on this work or any other Project Gutenberg-tm
work. The Foundation makes no representations concerning the copyright
status of any work in any country outside the United States.


1.E.


Unless you have removed all references to Project Gutenberg:


1.E.1.


The following sentence, with active links to, or other immediate access
to, the full Project Gutenberg-tm License must appear prominently whenever
any copy of a Project Gutenberg-tm work (any work on which the phrase
Project Gutenberg appears, or with which the phrase Project Gutenberg
is associated) is accessed, displayed, performed, viewed, copied or
distributed:


      This eBook is for the use of anyone anywhere at no cost and
      with almost no restrictions whatsoever. You may copy it, give
      it away or re-use it under the terms of the Project Gutenberg
      License included with this eBook or online at
      http://www.gutenberg.org


1.E.2.


If an individual Project Gutenberg-tm electronic work is derived from the
public domain (does not contain a notice indicating that it is posted with
permission of the copyright holder), the work can be copied and
distributed to anyone in the United States without paying any fees or
charges. If you are redistributing or providing access to a work with the
phrase Project Gutenberg associated with or appearing on the work, you
must comply either with the requirements of paragraphs 1.E.1 through 1.E.7
or obtain permission for the use of the work and the Project Gutenberg-tm
trademark as set forth in paragraphs 1.E.8 or 1.E.9.


1.E.3.


If an individual Project Gutenberg-tm electronic work is posted with the
permission of the copyright holder, your use and distribution must comply
with both paragraphs 1.E.1 through 1.E.7 and any additional terms imposed
by the copyright holder. Additional terms will be linked to the Project
Gutenberg-tm License for all works posted with the permission of the
copyright holder found at the beginning of this work.


1.E.4.


Do not unlink or detach or remove the full Project Gutenberg-tm License
terms from this work, or any files containing a part of this work or any
other work associated with Project Gutenberg-tm.


1.E.5.


Do not copy, display, perform, distribute or redistribute this electronic
work, or any part of this electronic work, without prominently displaying
the sentence set forth in paragraph 1.E.1 with active links or immediate
access to the full terms of the Project Gutenberg-tm License.


1.E.6.


You may convert to and distribute this work in any binary, compressed,
marked up, nonproprietary or proprietary form, including any word
processing or hypertext form. However, if you provide access to or
distribute copies of a Project Gutenberg-tm work in a format other than
Plain Vanilla ASCII or other format used in the official version posted
on the official Project Gutenberg-tm web site (http://www.gutenberg.org),
you must, at no additional cost, fee or expense to the user, provide a
copy, a means of exporting a copy, or a means of obtaining a copy upon
request, of the work in its original Plain Vanilla ASCII or other form.
Any alternate format must include the full Project Gutenberg-tm License as
specified in paragraph 1.E.1.


1.E.7.


Do not charge a fee for access to, viewing, displaying, performing,
copying or distributing any Project Gutenberg-tm works unless you comply
with paragraph 1.E.8 or 1.E.9.


1.E.8.


You may charge a reasonable fee for copies of or providing access to or
distributing Project Gutenberg-tm electronic works provided that

    - You pay a royalty fee of 20% of the gross profits you derive from
      the use of Project Gutenberg-tm works calculated using the method
      you already use to calculate your applicable taxes. The fee is owed
      to the owner of the Project Gutenberg-tm trademark, but he has
      agreed to donate royalties under this paragraph to the Project
      Gutenberg Literary Archive Foundation. Royalty payments must be paid
      within 60 days following each date on which you prepare (or are
      legally required to prepare) your periodic tax returns. Royalty
      payments should be clearly marked as such and sent to the Project
      Gutenberg Literary Archive Foundation at the address specified in
      Section 4, Information about donations to the Project Gutenberg
      Literary Archive Foundation.

    - You provide a full refund of any money paid by a user who notifies
      you in writing (or by e-mail) within 30 days of receipt that s/he
      does not agree to the terms of the full Project Gutenberg-tm
      License. You must require such a user to return or destroy all
      copies of the works possessed in a physical medium and discontinue
      all use of and all access to other copies of Project Gutenberg-tm
      works.

    - You provide, in accordance with paragraph 1.F.3, a full refund of
      any money paid for a work or a replacement copy, if a defect in the
      electronic work is discovered and reported to you within 90 days of
      receipt of the work.

    - You comply with all other terms of this agreement for free
      distribution of Project Gutenberg-tm works.


1.E.9.


If you wish to charge a fee or distribute a Project Gutenberg-tm
electronic work or group of works on different terms than are set forth in
this agreement, you must obtain permission in writing from both the
Project Gutenberg Literary Archive Foundation and Michael Hart, the owner
of the Project Gutenberg-tm trademark. Contact the Foundation as set forth
in Section 3 below.


1.F.


1.F.1.


Project Gutenberg volunteers and employees expend considerable effort to
identify, do copyright research on, transcribe and proofread public domain
works in creating the Project Gutenberg-tm collection. Despite these
efforts, Project Gutenberg-tm electronic works, and the medium on which
they may be stored, may contain Defects, such as, but not limited to,
incomplete, inaccurate or corrupt data, transcription errors, a copyright
or other intellectual property infringement, a defective or damaged disk
or other medium, a computer virus, or computer codes that damage or cannot
be read by your equipment.


1.F.2.


LIMITED WARRANTY, DISCLAIMER OF DAMAGES  Except for the Right of
Replacement or Refund described in paragraph 1.F.3, the Project Gutenberg
Literary Archive Foundation, the owner of the Project Gutenberg-tm
trademark, and any other party distributing a Project Gutenberg-tm
electronic work under this agreement, disclaim all liability to you for
damages, costs and expenses, including legal fees. YOU AGREE THAT YOU HAVE
NO REMEDIES FOR NEGLIGENCE, STRICT LIABILITY, BREACH OF WARRANTY OR BREACH
OF CONTRACT EXCEPT THOSE PROVIDED IN PARAGRAPH F3. YOU AGREE THAT THE
FOUNDATION, THE TRADEMARK OWNER, AND ANY DISTRIBUTOR UNDER THIS AGREEMENT
WILL NOT BE LIABLE TO YOU FOR ACTUAL, DIRECT, INDIRECT, CONSEQUENTIAL,
PUNITIVE OR INCIDENTAL DAMAGES EVEN IF YOU GIVE NOTICE OF THE POSSIBILITY
OF SUCH DAMAGE.


1.F.3.


LIMITED RIGHT OF REPLACEMENT OR REFUND  If you discover a defect in this
electronic work within 90 days of receiving it, you can receive a refund
of the money (if any) you paid for it by sending a written explanation to
the person you received the work from. If you received the work on a
physical medium, you must return the medium with your written explanation.
The person or entity that provided you with the defective work may elect
to provide a replacement copy in lieu of a refund. If you received the
work electronically, the person or entity providing it to you may choose
to give you a second opportunity to receive the work electronically in
lieu of a refund. If the second copy is also defective, you may demand a
refund in writing without further opportunities to fix the problem.


1.F.4.


Except for the limited right of replacement or refund set forth in
paragraph 1.F.3, this work is provided to you AS-IS, WITH NO OTHER
WARRANTIES OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO
WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTIBILITY OR FITNESS FOR ANY PURPOSE.


1.F.5.


Some states do not allow disclaimers of certain implied warranties or the
exclusion or limitation of certain types of damages. If any disclaimer or
limitation set forth in this agreement violates the law of the state
applicable to this agreement, the agreement shall be interpreted to make
the maximum disclaimer or limitation permitted by the applicable state
law. The invalidity or unenforceability of any provision of this agreement
shall not void the remaining provisions.


1.F.6.


INDEMNITY  You agree to indemnify and hold the Foundation, the trademark
owner, any agent or employee of the Foundation, anyone providing copies of
Project Gutenberg-tm electronic works in accordance with this agreement,
and any volunteers associated with the production, promotion and
distribution of Project Gutenberg-tm electronic works, harmless from all
liability, costs and expenses, including legal fees, that arise directly
or indirectly from any of the following which you do or cause to occur:
(a) distribution of this or any Project Gutenberg-tm work, (b) alteration,
modification, or additions or deletions to any Project Gutenberg-tm work,
and (c) any Defect you cause.



Section  2.


          Information about the Mission of Project Gutenberg-tm


Project Gutenberg-tm is synonymous with the free distribution of
electronic works in formats readable by the widest variety of computers
including obsolete, old, middle-aged and new computers. It exists because
of the efforts of hundreds of volunteers and donations from people in all
walks of life.

Volunteers and financial support to provide volunteers with the assistance
they need, is critical to reaching Project Gutenberg-tms goals and
ensuring that the Project Gutenberg-tm collection will remain freely
available for generations to come. In 2001, the Project Gutenberg Literary
Archive Foundation was created to provide a secure and permanent future
for Project Gutenberg-tm and future generations. To learn more about the
Project Gutenberg Literary Archive Foundation and how your efforts and
donations can help, see Sections 3 and 4 and the Foundation web page at
http://www.pglaf.org.



Section 3.


   Information about the Project Gutenberg Literary Archive Foundation


The Project Gutenberg Literary Archive Foundation is a non profit
501(c)(3) educational corporation organized under the laws of the state of
Mississippi and granted tax exempt status by the Internal Revenue Service.
The Foundations EIN or federal tax identification number is 64-6221541.
Its 501(c)(3) letter is posted at http://www.pglaf.org/fundraising.
Contributions to the Project Gutenberg Literary Archive Foundation are tax
deductible to the full extent permitted by U.S. federal laws and your
states laws.

The Foundations principal office is located at 4557 Melan Dr.
S. Fairbanks, AK, 99712., but its volunteers and employees are scattered
throughout numerous locations. Its business office is located at 809 North
1500 West, Salt Lake City, UT 84116, (801) 596-1887, email
business@pglaf.org. Email contact links and up to date contact information
can be found at the Foundations web site and official page at
http://www.pglaf.org

For additional contact information:


      Dr. Gregory B. Newby
      Chief Executive and Director
      gbnewby@pglaf.org



Section 4.


  Information about Donations to the Project Gutenberg Literary Archive
                                Foundation


Project Gutenberg-tm depends upon and cannot survive without wide spread
public support and donations to carry out its mission of increasing the
number of public domain and licensed works that can be freely distributed
in machine readable form accessible by the widest array of equipment
including outdated equipment. Many small donations ($1 to $5,000) are
particularly important to maintaining tax exempt status with the IRS.

The Foundation is committed to complying with the laws regulating
charities and charitable donations in all 50 states of the United States.
Compliance requirements are not uniform and it takes a considerable
effort, much paperwork and many fees to meet and keep up with these
requirements. We do not solicit donations in locations where we have not
received written confirmation of compliance. To SEND DONATIONS or
determine the status of compliance for any particular state visit
http://www.pglaf.org

While we cannot and do not solicit contributions from states where we have
not met the solicitation requirements, we know of no prohibition against
accepting unsolicited donations from donors in such states who approach us
with offers to donate.

International donations are gratefully accepted, but we cannot make any
statements concerning tax treatment of donations received from outside the
United States. U.S. laws alone swamp our small staff.

Please check the Project Gutenberg Web pages for current donation methods
and addresses. Donations are accepted in a number of other ways including
checks, online payments and credit card donations. To donate, please
visit: http://www.pglaf.org/donate



Section 5.


     General Information About Project Gutenberg-tm electronic works.


Professor Michael S. Hart is the originator of the Project Gutenberg-tm
concept of a library of electronic works that could be freely shared with
anyone. For thirty years, he produced and distributed Project Gutenberg-tm
eBooks with only a loose network of volunteer support.

Project Gutenberg-tm eBooks are often created from several printed
editions, all of which are confirmed as Public Domain in the U.S. unless a
copyright notice is included. Thus, we do not necessarily keep eBooks in
compliance with any particular paper edition.

Each eBook is in a subdirectory of the same number as the eBooks eBook
number, often in several formats including plain vanilla ASCII, compressed
(zipped), HTML and others.

Corrected _editions_ of our eBooks replace the old file and take over the
old filename and etext number. The replaced older file is renamed.
_Versions_ based on separate sources are treated as new eBooks receiving
new filenames and etext numbers.

Most people start at our Web site which has the main PG search facility:


      http://www.gutenberg.org


This Web site includes information about Project Gutenberg-tm, including
how to make donations to the Project Gutenberg Literary Archive
Foundation, how to help produce our new eBooks, and how to subscribe to
our email newsletter to hear about new eBooks.

-->
